<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:a10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0">
  <channel xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Microsoft Azure Blog &gt; Updates</title>
    <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/topics/updates/</link>
    <description />
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 15:39:05 Z</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link
      href="https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/feed/"
      rel="self"
      type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">sharing-the-latest-improvements-to-efficiency-in-microsoft-s-datacenters</guid>
      <category>Cloud Strategy</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <title>Sharing the latest improvements to efficiency in Microsoft’s datacenters</title>
      <description>Our objective moving forward is to continue providing transparency across the entire datacenter lifecycle about how we infuse principles of reliability, sustainability, and innovation at each step of the datacenter design, construction, and operations process.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 08:00:47 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In April, I published &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/how-microsoft-measures-datacenter-water-and-energy-use-to-improve-azure-cloud-sustainability" target="_blank"&gt;a blog&lt;/a&gt; that explained how we define and measure energy and water use at our datacenters, and how we are committed to continuous improvements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in the lead up to COP27, the global climate conference to be held in Egypt, I am pleased to provide a number of updates on how we&amp;rsquo;re progressing in making our datacenters more efficient across areas such as waste, renewables, and ecosystems. You can also visit &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/explore/global-infrastructure/sustainability/#overview"&gt;Azure Sustainability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/explore/global-infrastructure/sustainability/#overview"&gt;&amp;mdash;Sustainable Technologies | Microsoft Azure&lt;/a&gt; to explore this further.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Localized fact sheets in 28 regions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;To share important information about the impact of our datacenters regionally with our customers, we have published localized fact sheets in 28 regions across the globe. These fact sheets provide a wide range of information and details about many different aspects of our datacenters and their operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/a0adbef0-c83f-4e2f-ba20-c9f05786fec7.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="A screenshot of a globe. " border="0" height="512" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/4f9bd898-ce6a-42e1-b23a-73bb575b4da9.jpg" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="1" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;A review of PUE (Power Usage Effectiveness) and WUE (Water Usage Effectiveness)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/a3c8edec-c572-4fa6-ae77-d0a478390bb9.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A factsheet with data around Microsoft's Ireland datacenter region. " border="0" height="767" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/42f745ad-674b-498a-917e-7af4afe403ee.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="2" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PUE&lt;/strong&gt; is an industry metric that measures how efficiently a datacenter consumes and uses the energy that powers a datacenter, including the operation of systems like powering, cooling, and operating the servers, data networks and lights. The closer the PUE number is to &amp;ldquo;1,&amp;rdquo; the more efficient the use of energy.&lt;br&gt;&#xD;
While local environment and infrastructure can affect how PUE is calculated, there are also slight variations across providers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the simplest way to think about PUE:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/230d538b-3ec7-4074-bb7a-4b57fc219c60.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A picture of Power Usage Effectiveness (PUE) calculation." border="0" height="34" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/e9f361a2-d080-4946-ba20-425209d8a962.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="506"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WUE&lt;/strong&gt; is another key metric relating to the efficient and sustainable operations of our datacenters and is a crucial aspect as we work towards our commitment to be &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/green-tech-blog/part-three-water-positive-zero-waste-and-ecosystems/ba-p/2224123"&gt;water positive&lt;/a&gt; by 2030. WUE is calculated by dividing the number of liters of water used for humidification and cooling by the total annual amount of power (measured in kWh) needed to operate our datacenter IT equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/31eb6438-316c-4b85-9cac-304dcc93223d.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A picture of a Water Usage Effectiveness calculation." border="0" height="37" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/e71ad504-c24e-4614-82cb-d2fcce56d1d4.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="579"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to PUE and WUE, below are key highlights across carbon, water, and waste initiatives at our datacenters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Datacenter efficiency in North and South America&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;As I illustrated in April, our newest generation of datacenters have a design PUE of 1.12; this includes our Chile datacenter that is under construction. We are constantly focused on improving our energy efficiency, for example in California, our San Jose datacenters will be cooled with an indirect evaporative cooling system using reclaimed water all year and zero fresh water. Because the new datacenter facilities will be cooled with reclaimed water, they will have a WUE of 0.00 L/kWh in terms of freshwater usage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, as we continue our journey to achieve zero waste by 2030, we are proud of the progress we are making with our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IcWg7F85puY" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Circular Centers&lt;/a&gt;. These centers sit adjacent to a Microsoft datacenter and process decommissioned cloud servers and hardware. Our teams sort and intelligently channel the components and equipment to optimize, reuse or repurpose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In October, we launched a Circular Center in Chicago, Illinois that has the potential capacity to process up to 12,000 servers per month for reuse, diverting up to 144,000 servers annually. We plan to open a Circular Center in Washington state early next year and have plans for Circular Centers in Texas, Iowa, and Arizona to further optimize our supply chain and reduce waste.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, our team has successfully completed an important water reuse project at one of our datacenters. This treatment facility, &lt;a href="https://local.microsoft.com/blog/partnering-with-the-city-of-quincy-to-open-washingtons-first-industrial-water-reuse-center/"&gt;the first of its kind&lt;/a&gt; in Washington state and over 10 years in the making, will process water for reuse by local industries, including datacenters, decreasing the need for potable water for datacenter cooling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Innovative solutions in Europe, the Middle East, and Africa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This winter Europeans face the possibility of an energy crisis, and we have made a number of investments in optimizing energy efficiency in our datacenters to ensure that we are operating our facilities as effectively as possible. Datacenters are the &lt;a href="https://news.microsoft.com/europe/features/critical-to-our-modern-society-how-datacenters-power-everyday-necessities/"&gt;backbone of modern society&lt;/a&gt; and as such it is important that we continue to provide critical services to the industries that need us most in a way that constantly mitigates energy consumption.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Across our datacenters in EMEA, we have made steady progress across carbon, waste, water, and ecosystems. We are committed to shifting to 100 percent renewable energy supply by 2025, meaning that we will have power purchase agreements for green energy contracted for 100 percent of carbon emitting electricity consumed by all our data centers, buildings, and campuses. This will add additional gigawatts of renewable energy to the grid, increasing energy capacity. We&amp;#39;re helping to add clean capacity to the grid by signing purchase agreements for more than 5 gigawatts of renewable energy around the world. Those agreements include more than 15 individual deals in Europe spanning Ireland, Denmark, Sweden, and Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In Finland, we recently announced &lt;a href="https://news.microsoft.com/europe/2022/03/17/microsoft-announces-intent-to-build-a-new-datacenter-region-in-finland-accelerating-sustainable-digital-transformation-and-enabling-large-scale-carbon-free-district-heating/#:~:text=In%20a%20unique%20collaboration%20with%20Fortum%20Corporation%2C%20the,scheme%20to%20recycle%20waste%20heat%20from%20data%20centers." target="_blank"&gt;an important heat reuse project&lt;/a&gt; that will take excess heat from our datacenters and transfer that heat to the local districts&amp;rsquo; heating systems that can be used for both domestic and commercial purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;To reduce waste from our datacenters in EMEA, the Circular Center &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/blog/learn-how-microsoft-circular-centers-are-scaling-cloud-supply-chain-sustainability/"&gt;we opened in Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; in 2020, which has since already delivered an 83 percent reuse of end-of-life datacenter assets and components. This is progress towards our target of 90 percent reuse and recycling of all servers and components for all cloud hardware by 2025. In addition, in January 2022, we opened a Circular Center in Dublin, Ireland, and have plans to open another Circular Center in Sweden to serve the region.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;As we continue to seek out efficiencies in our operations, recently we turned to nature for inspiration, to understand how much of the natural ecosystem we could replenish on the site of a datacenter, essentially integrating the datacenter into nature with the goal of renewing and revitalizing the surrounding area so that we can restore and create a pathway to provide regenerative value for the local community and environment. In the Netherlands we have begun construction of a lowland forested area around the datacenter as well as forested wetland. This was done to support the growth of native plants to mirror a healthy, resilient ecosystem and support biodiversity, improve storm water control and prevent erosion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/84d145f4-1a4a-4623-bbe2-f88ee8de3843.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rendering of a biomimicry project in the Netherlands showing a concept of using nature to cover the datacenter. Image of an actual datacenter. " border="0" height="297" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/c477d475-c34c-4773-891e-a1bf34ad1e60.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Updates in Asia Pacific&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I&amp;rsquo;d like to highlight some of the sustainability investments we have made across Asia Pacific. In June 2022, we launched our &lt;a href="https://news.microsoft.com/en-sg/2022/09/07/opening-doors-to-a-sustainable-future-with-microsofts-circular-center-in-singapore/"&gt;Singapore Circular Center&lt;/a&gt; that is capable of processing up to 3,000 servers per month for reuse, or 36,000 servers annually. We have plans to open additional Circular Centers in Australia and South Korea in fiscal year 2025 and beyond. Across our datacenters in APAC, &lt;a href="https://news.microsoft.com/en-au/features/microsoft-takes-another-key-step-to-reduce-data-centre-emissions-in-anz" target="_blank"&gt;we have formed partnerships with local energy providers&lt;/a&gt; for renewable energy that is sourced from wind, solar, and hydro power and we have plans to further these partnerships and investments in renewable energy. In our forthcoming datacenter region in &lt;a href="https://news.microsoft.com/en-nz/2022/08/18/conscious-cloud-our-aotearoa-datacenter-pledge-microsofts-datacenter-region-powered-by-100-carbon-free-energy-from-day-one/"&gt;New Zealand&lt;/a&gt;, we have signed an agreement that will enable Microsoft to power all of its datacenters with 100 percent renewable energy from the day it opens.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Innovating to design the hyperscale datacenter of the future&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;What these examples from across our global datacenter portfolio show is our ongoing commitment to make our global Microsoft datacenters more sustainable and efficient, enabling our customers to do more with less.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Our objective moving forward is to continue providing transparency across the entire datacenter lifecycle about how we infuse principles of reliability, sustainability, and innovation at each step of the datacenter design, construction, and operations process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;: How do we ensure we design for reliability, efficiency, and sustainability, to help reduce our customers&amp;#39; scope three emissions?&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Construction&lt;/strong&gt;: How do we reduce embodied carbon and create a reliable supply chain?&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operation&lt;/strong&gt;: How do we infuse innovative green technologies to decarbonize and operate to the efficient design standards?&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decommissioning&lt;/strong&gt;: How do we recycle and reuse materials in our datacenters?&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;: How do we partner with the community and operate as good neighbors?&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We have started by sharing datacenter region-specific data around carbon, water, waste, ecosystems, and community development and we will continue to provide updates as Microsoft makes further investments globally.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about our global datacenter footprint across the 60+ datacenter regions by visiting &lt;a href="https://datacenters.microsoft.com"&gt;datacenters.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;View our Microsoft datacenter &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/SustainabilityFactsheets"&gt;factsheets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/explore/global-infrastructure/sustainability/#overview" target="_blank"&gt;Azure sustainability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Discover &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/WAF/sustainability" target="_blank"&gt;new sustainability guidance in the Azure Well-Architected Framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Take a &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/virtualdatacentertour"&gt;virtual tour&lt;/a&gt; of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s datacenters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/sharing-the-latest-improvements-to-efficiency-in-microsoft-s-datacenters/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/sharing-the-latest-improvements-to-efficiency-in-microsoft-s-datacenters/</link>
      <dc:creator>Noelle Walsh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">accenture-and-microsoft-drive-digital-transformation-with-oneplatform-on-microsoft-energy-data-services-for-osdu</guid>
      <category>Big Data</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <category>Partner</category>
      <title>Accenture and Microsoft drive digital transformation with OnePlatform on Microsoft Energy Data Services for OSDU™</title>
      <description>Accenture is focused on connecting data to business value and working with Microsoft to deliver a fully integrated approach using the OSDU Data Platform to accelerate digital transformation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 08:00:24 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was co-authored by Sacha Abinader, Managing Director, Accenture and Keith Armstrong, Senior Manager, Accenture Microsoft Business Group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Accelerate decision-making and interoperability with the OSDU Data Platform&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The OSDU&amp;trade; Forum is a cross-industry collaboration to develop a common, standards-based, and open platform for the exploration and production (E&amp;amp;P) community with the goal to liberate and enable greater access and insight into your valuable data. The OSDU Data Platform promise is compelling and offers value beyond what can be achieved with in-house solutions through established industry standards and openness to the larger technology ecosystem. Accenture has partnered with Microsoft and collaborated closely with Schlumberger during the Microsoft Energy Data Services preview and development process. In addition to Accenture&amp;rsquo;s domain expertise and digital integration acumen, the preview experience has allowed Accenture to develop skills and scale a team specific to this offering to enable an operator&amp;rsquo;s OSDU Data Platform journey at pace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;As such, the OSDU Data Platform as an industry solution has been a top priority for Accenture with significant investments in skills, people, assets, and our presence and leadership as part of the OSDU Forum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;We are thrilled to be a services partner for Microsoft Energy Data Services. The partnership with Microsoft and Schlumberger in enabling an open platform has been wonderful. As part of preview, Accenture has been driving for interoperability across the technology ecosystem to bridge siloed teams and has partnered with Schlumberger and several ISVs to make this a reality. We are excited to enable operators to create additional value through improved and accelerated decision making and the development of new workflows and analytics.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Emma Wild, Managing Director, Global OSDU Lead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Accenture has been actively involved in the OSDU Data Platform initiative for several years. In addition to our commitment to the OSDU Forum, we have developed our own vision and strategy as to how we can support OSDU Data Platform integration into E&amp;amp;P workflows and how we can increase operators&amp;#39; business capability and data value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Accenture understands our clients&amp;rsquo; challenges and is their partner for complex transformations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Our partners and clients want access to secure, clean, and curated data. To achieve this, they must liberate and migrate their data to the OSDU Data Platform. Our clients are dealing with large and highly complex data sets that have varying quality and formats. They also need to manage their ongoing business using the current and future capabilities of the OSDU Data Platform with its continual improvements of new data types and features. Accenture has planned a strategy that supports the transition from monolithic apps and data to the OSDU Data Platform at pace. Accenture and Microsoft are partners on this transformational journey as seen in &lt;em&gt;Figure 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/27aed989-3e54-4fac-a52e-812aaaa1b81f.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Accenture’s OSDU capabilities and differentiators, Data Migration, Business Continuity, Data to Insights and Scale to business value at pace" border="0" height="340" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/bebca100-3fda-45ac-ba69-4a0a37bed84f.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="Picture1a" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Our vision, your value&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;To be successful we believe there is a need to create and support a solution that provides an end-to-end business capability, focusing on &lt;strong&gt;business value&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;time-to-value acceleration&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/a62b3e37-2047-4ea4-bce2-37509ad554d9.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Accelerating business value through data by finding, validating and preparing your data, improving data quality, accessing and visualizing, providing a one stop data shop, emerging technologies and analytics and providing enhanced business capabilities  " border="0" height="194" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/b53eee04-cc37-4b7b-88e5-28f35901f87f.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="Picture2a" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Our approach will quickly prepare and present data to the user via the OSDU Data Platform irrespective of its current functionality and capability. By integrating and consolidating data in a standard format and enabling the interoperability of the platform across ISVs, operators can unlock the milestones to the right of the diagram and deliver the accelerated value they&amp;rsquo;ve been promised.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We think of it as supporting a data life cycle and journey to mitigate perceived risks due to the evolving nature of the OSDU Data Platform while continually improving your business workflows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Why choose Microsoft Energy Data Services?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize the complexity and risks involved in the transition and migration to the OSDU Data Platform. While energy companies have always managed E&amp;amp;P risk and uncertainty, there is generally a much lower appetite when it comes to IT and digital platforms. As a result, the industry is increasingly seeking packaged solutions or out-of-the-box delivery structures. This enables them to realize the visions promised by the OSDU Data Platform yet still focus on the &amp;quot;day job&amp;quot; and running their operations and business. These solutions and structures help de-risk the journey and minimize disruption to business continuity. Recognizing this, Microsoft developed an open-packaged solution to offer the OSDU Data Platform as a PaaS through Microsoft Energy Data Services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Energy Data Services was designed to support the energy industry&amp;rsquo;s ambition to accelerate innovation, develop enhanced insights to drive operational efficiency, and inform new ways of working and workflows. Microsoft Energy Data Services can accelerate the journey to a cloud-based OSDU Data Platform and thus, the path to value.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Accenture and Microsoft Energy Data Services collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Accenture has helped deploy and test Microsoft Energy Data Services through the preview stages to provide feedback to Microsoft Engineering. Accenture is focused on connecting data to business value and working with Microsoft to deliver a fully integrated approach using the OSDU Data Platform to accelerate digital transformation. Accenture demonstrated this during the preview by deploying the Microsoft Energy Data Services solution, ingesting data with OSDU core service tools and Accenture proprietary tools, and stitching together a data workflow across multiple ISVs to validate the openness of the platform. During this process, Accenture has built a team that can help deploy and scale on Microsoft Energy Data Services.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Energy Data Services differentiates itself as it will allow and enable:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Integration with virtually any energy dataset, application, or cloud service with built-in tools.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Management for compute-intensive workloads at a global scale.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Compliance with the OSDU Technical Standard for open source innovation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Ease the deployment of the OSDU Data Platform while providing ongoing platform and management support to align to OSDU Data Platform deployments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Rapid data ingestion for analytics and decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Increase operational efficiency and gain global scalability while reducing operational costs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Comprehensive security and compliance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Ability to easily leverage native Azure and Microsoft solutions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Energy Data Services further builds on and enables the OSDU Data Platform value drivers:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;The ability to access clean and curated historical data under a single data platform.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Open access to innovation and a wider set of technology partners (ISVs).&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Removes siloes and barriers between disciplines and lays the foundation for digital transformation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Accenture&amp;rsquo;s specific capabilities and toolkit&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Data on its own is not the answer, and Accenture has been working hard to offer end-to-end services and tools which connect the full enterprise and business. The journey requires the need to deliver clean data to unlock value through data science, deploy, and roll out these solutions across global operations, and importantly, to instill trust from end users and the business to allow the value to be recognized.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/4bdd5846-e9d9-4d13-ba5d-82af22f2bc40.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Accenture’s OnePlatform and associated offerings that integrates with Microsoft energy data services." border="0" height="576" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/22f366fa-e5ac-41e0-87f5-469c4fb61b51.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Accenture is spearheading the industry adoption of the OSDU Data Platform to enable energy companies to accelerate their digital transformation. One such platform we are developing is the &lt;strong&gt;Accenture OnePlatform&lt;/strong&gt;, as seen in &lt;em&gt;Figures 3&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, which is a working solution to address the current issues and challenges and help execute the data to its maximum limit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/4f8a9569-4e17-4e3a-81ed-b86bf71de20c.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Accenture’s OnePlatform Data Workflow that comprises identify data and prepare, ingest data and conditioning, visualize data and interoperability, interpret data and AI and data analysis and insights" border="0" height="270" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/83ccb389-6079-4374-a444-c76881b96f7e.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="Picture4a" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 4: &lt;/strong&gt;Accenture&amp;#39;s OnePlatform Data Workflow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Accenture OnePlatform is a cloud-agnostic platform and one-stop solution for data extraction, schema mapping, metadata generation, and data ingestion that is operationally efficient. Accenture OnePlatform enables OSDU Data Platform services that are available with just one click without any need for extra plugins or any open source installations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the key highlights of Accenture OnePlatform are outlined below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchestration of the OSDU Data Platform&lt;/strong&gt;: Provide end-to-end delivery of business workflows via a single interface.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data extraction&lt;/strong&gt;: Extracting different data types by using a data type converter such as LAS, SegY, or ResQML.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schema Mapping&lt;/strong&gt;: Mapping client data with Accenture OnePlatform&amp;ndash;compliant data types by using AI/ML models.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metadata Generation&lt;/strong&gt;: Generating metadata by using AI rule-based approach.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Ingestion&lt;/strong&gt;: Ingestion workflow. Running on click solution using python utilities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Validation&lt;/strong&gt;: Validating records using python utilities by adding customized rules.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Quality&lt;/strong&gt;: Intelligent way to set up the rules and do the quality checks automatically.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Graph&lt;/strong&gt;: Build Accenture OnePlatform-based ontology and give the semantic result to the customer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Accenture OnePlatform can serve as an orchestration tool across multiple SaaS ISV solutions. We know interoperability is a key value driver for choosing OSDU. Accenture has played a major role in ISV&amp;rsquo;s integration by collaborating with various ISVs and Microsoft for collective purpose of consuming the data available in single data platform. Accenture is working with several leading ISVs for development of their applications to fetch data according to the schemas from the OSDU Data Platform and Microsoft Energy Data Services, offering best-in-class interoperability and the ability to deliver end-to-end business workflows. Microsoft Energy Data Services with Accenture&amp;rsquo;s support has demonstrated the integration of DELFI with multiple ISV applications, such as Interica and Ikon Science, and we were pleased to demonstrate this at the Schlumberger Digital Forum 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, Accenture is committed to being a leading partner to help operators navigate the uncertainties around OSDU Data Platform implementation, manage the risks of deployment, and realize the full value of their data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We believe Accenture is best placed to deliver on these commitments and enable your value based on our deep industry expertise, investments in accelerators like the Accenture OnePlatform, 14,000+ dedicated oil and gas skilled global practitioners with 250+ OSDU&amp;trade;-trained professionals, and our extensive ecosystem relationships. We are confident that our capabilities and our partnership with Microsoft are key to helping operators execute and scale their OSDU Data Platform transformation with Microsoft Energy Data Services and the interoperability of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;How to work with Accenture on Microsoft Energy Data Services&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Energy Data Services is an enterprise-grade, fully managed, OSDU Data Platform for the energy industry that is efficient, standardized, easy to deploy, and scalable for data management&amp;mdash;for ingesting, aggregating, storing, searching, and retrieving data. The platform will provide the scale, security, privacy, and compliance expected by our enterprise customers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://aka.ms/microsoftenergydataservices" target="_blank"&gt;Get started with Microsoft Energy Data Services today.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.accenture.com/us-en/services/energy/osdu" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more about Accenture&amp;rsquo;s OSDU Capabilities.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/accenture-and-microsoft-drive-digital-transformation-with-oneplatform-on-microsoft-energy-data-services-for-osdu/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/accenture-and-microsoft-drive-digital-transformation-with-oneplatform-on-microsoft-energy-data-services-for-osdu/</link>
      <dc:creator>Kadri  Umay</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">forrester-total-economic-impact-study-azure-arc-delivers-206-percent-roi-over-3-years</guid>
      <category>Security</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <title>Forrester Total Economic Impact study: Azure Arc delivers 206 percent ROI over 3 years</title>
      <description>Azure Arc is a bridge that extends the Azure platform so you can build applications and services with the flexibility to run across datacenters, edge, and multicloud environments.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 08:00:25 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Businesses today are building and running cloud-based applications to drive their business forward. As these applications are built they need to take full advantage of the agility, efficiency, and speed of cloud innovation. However, not all applications and infrastructure they run on can physically reside in the public cloud. That&amp;rsquo;s why &lt;a href="https://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2022/01/27/cloud-trends-show-customers-increasing-investments-in-hybrid-and-multicloud" target="_blank"&gt;86 percent of enterprises&lt;/a&gt; plan to increase investment in hybrid or multicloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re building Azure to meet you where you are, so you can do more with your existing investments. We also want you to be able to stay agile and flexible when extending Azure to your on-premises, multicloud, and edge environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/azure-arc"&gt;Azure Arc&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;delivers on these needs. Azure Arc is a bridge that extends the Azure platform so you can build applications and services with the flexibility to run across datacenters, edge, and multicloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/772166c9-d5f1-448b-b5f5-efbe2d05ea63.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Azure Arc is a set of technologies from Microsoft that is a bridge that extends the Azure platform so customers can build applications and services with the flexibility to run across datacenters, edge, and multicloud environments." border="0" height="347" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/1f790f9c-78de-44d1-a757-af3cc9d2a547.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="d5ab52ae-c105-4e7c-9d5f-f333c3063243" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;For the 2022 commissioned study, &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/arc-forresterstudy"&gt;The Total Economic Impact&amp;trade; of Microsoft Azure Arc for Security and Governance&lt;/a&gt;, Forrester Consulting interviewed four organizations with experience using Azure Arc. These organizations serve global markets in the industries of manufacturing, energy, and financial services.&amp;nbsp;According to the aggregated data, Azure Arc demonstrated:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;A 206 percent return on investment (ROI) over three years with payback in less than six months.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;A 30 percent gain in productivity for IT Operations team members.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;An 80 percent reduction in risk of data breach from unsecured infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;A 15 percent reduction in spending on third-party tools, saving on expenses.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The Forrester study provides a framework for organizations wanting to evaluate the potential financial impact on their organizations of using Azure Arc for infrastructure security and governance. Forrester found that organizations with hybrid or multicloud strategies can realize productivity gains and reduce security risks by using Microsoft Azure Arc to secure and govern non-Azure infrastructure alongside Azure resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Productivity gains with Azure Arc&amp;rsquo;s single-pane view&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The organizations in Forrester&amp;rsquo;s study reported that after implementing Azure Arc, their IT Operations personnel realized a &lt;strong&gt;30 percent gain in productivity&lt;/strong&gt; from savings in time spent on regular duties such as configuring and updating infrastructure, managing policies and permissions, troubleshooting, and resolving issues, and other tasks that don&amp;rsquo;t directly drive business. With Azure Arc, IT teams can observe, secure, and govern diverse infrastructure and applications from a single pane of glass in Azure&amp;mdash;leveraging Azure services enables them to be more agile, respond more efficiently, and frees time to serve business interests with higher-value tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re just making everyone&amp;rsquo;s lives so much easier so they can do other things. If there is an issue, for example, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to spend a week troubleshooting.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Architect, Cloud products, Energy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Cost savings and streamlined infrastructure through the Azure portal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Most organizations today run a mix of applications in on-premises datacenters, in the cloud, and at the edge. These disparate environments often result in investments in multiple management tools specific to the technology platforms, resulting in tool sprawl and excessive costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;By moving to a single view of infrastructure and resources in the Azure portal enabled by Azure Arc, organizations could eliminate their legacy management tools, reducing licensing expenditures and eliminating costly on-premises management infrastructure. With Azure&amp;rsquo;s flexible consumption-based pricing, they are no longer locked into long-term contracts or capacity limits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The composite organization in the Forrester study saved $900,000 in year three from reduced spending on third-party tools&amp;mdash;&lt;strong&gt;a 15 percent decrease.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;When I do dive in, I actually have a faster understanding of [our infrastructure]. So the benefit to me is that I have greater visibility&lt;/i&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;i&gt;I need to ask [the team] fewer questions. The [Azure Arc] dashboard is [&amp;hellip;] very easy.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;VP of IT, Finance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud and Microsoft Sentinel modernize security operations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Arc helps organizations combat rapidly evolving security threats with increased efficiency by enabling the use of Microsoft security services such as Microsoft Defender for Cloud and Microsoft Sentinel across hybrid and multicloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Forrester found that the composite&amp;nbsp;organization lowered the&lt;strong&gt; risk of a data breach from unsecured infrastructure by 80 percent&lt;/strong&gt; after adopting Azure Arc and Microsoft security services. After onboarding Azure Arc, the organization uncovered noncompliant assets running on-premises or in edge environments and updated them to the latest security standards. This results in the savings of hundreds of thousands of dollars that would have been spent otherwise on managing breaches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;With Azure Arc, we gained real insights into our infrastructure, including infrastructure [another cloud provider]. That helped us identify architecture [gaps] as well as controls to improve security compliance. [With Azure Arc], we found that around 20 percent of our infrastructure had been noncompliant.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;Deputy IT Director, Manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Arc is a bridge that extends the Azure platform to help customers build applications and services with the flexibility to run across datacenters, at the edge, and in multicloud environments. Get started today and do more with your existing investments. We welcome you to &lt;a href="https://ms.portal.azure.com/#view/Microsoft_Azure_HybridCompute/AzureArcCenterBlade/~/overview" target="_blank"&gt;try it for free&lt;/a&gt;. You can also learn more about how other &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/arc-customerstories" target="_blank"&gt;customers are using Azure Arc&lt;/a&gt; to innovate anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Download the full &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/arc-forresterstudy" target="_blank"&gt;report: The Total Economic Impact&amp;trade; of Microsoft Azure Arc for Security and Governance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;To learn more about Azure Arc, &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/azure-arc"&gt;visit our website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/forrester-total-economic-impact-study-azure-arc-delivers-206-percent-roi-over-3-years/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/forrester-total-economic-impact-study-azure-arc-delivers-206-percent-roi-over-3-years/</link>
      <dc:creator>Omar Khan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">introducing-vision-studio-a-uibased-demo-interface-for-computer-vision</guid>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
      <title>Introducing Vision Studio, a UI-based demo interface for Computer Vision</title>
      <description>Are you looking to improve the analysis and management of images and videos? The Computer Vision API provides access to advanced algorithms for processing media and returning information.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 08:00:08 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Are you looking to improve the analysis and management of images and videos? The Computer Vision API provides access to advanced algorithms for processing media and returning information. By uploading a media asset or specifying a media asset&amp;rsquo;s URL, Azure&amp;rsquo;s Computer Vision algorithms can analyze visual content in different ways based on inputs and user choices, tailored to your business.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Want to try out this service with samples that return data in a quick, straightforward manner, without technical support? We are happy to introduce &lt;a href="https://portal.vision.cognitive.azure.com" target="_blank"&gt;Vision Studio&lt;/a&gt; in preview, a platform of UI-based tools that lets you explore, demo and evaluate features from Computer Vision, regardless of your coding experience. You can start experimenting with the services and learning what they offer, then when ready to deploy, use the available client libraries and REST APIs to get started embedding these services into your own applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview of Vision Studio&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/3efc3cbf-9821-4705-b736-4ab32d20b06c.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image displaying the Vision Studio interface with multiple services available to try. The interface includes multiple tabs, which indicate additional product demos to experience." border="0" height="607" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/97d85a19-b0dc-47b0-8532-dc8f7b366e05.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Each of the Computer Vision features has one or more try-it-out experiences in Vision Studio. To use your own images in Vision Studio, you&amp;#39;ll need an Azure subscription and a resource for Cognitive Services for authentication. Otherwise, you can try Vision Studio without logging in, using our provided set of sample images. These experiences help you quickly test the features using a no-code approach that provides JSON and text responses. In Vision Studio, you can try out the following services:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;#39;s new to try in Vision Studio&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Optical Character Recognition (OCR)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The optical character recognition (OCR) service allows you to extract printed or handwritten text from images, such as photos of street signs and products, as well as from documents&amp;mdash;invoices, bills, financial reports, articles, and more. Try it out in Vision Studio using your own images to extract text.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Spatial Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The Spatial Analysis service analyzes the presence and movement of people on a video feed and produces events that other systems can respond to. Try it out in Vision Studio using samples we provide, to see how spatial analysis will improve retail operations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Face&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The Face service provides AI algorithms that detect, recognize, and analyze human faces in images. Facial recognition software is important in many different scenarios, such as identity verification, touchless access control, and face blurring for privacy. Apply for access to the Face API service to try out identity recognition and verification in Vision Studio.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Image Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The Image Analysis service extracts many visual features from images, such as objects, faces, adult content, and auto-generated text descriptions to improve accessibility. Try it out in Vision Studio using your own images to accurately identify objects, moderate content and caption images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/8ee456ff-066f-4db0-9d4f-005d340094be.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image displaying the Object Detection service demo. The image shows three people sitting at a table, and on the right, a list of the things detected in the image including people and a table." border="0" height="614" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/81ec7da1-a06a-4bde-8b1b-ae87ee607b28.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Responsible AI in Vision&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We offer guidance for the responsible use of these capabilities based on Microsoft AI&amp;rsquo;s principles of fairness, reliability and safety, privacy and security, inclusiveness, transparency, and human accountability. The Responsible AI Standard sets out our best thinking on how we will build AI systems to uphold these values and earn society&amp;rsquo;s trust. It provides specific, actionable guidance for our teams that goes beyond the high-level principles that have dominated the AI landscape to date. &amp;nbsp;Learn more about &lt;a href="https://portal.vision.cognitive.azure.com/responsibleAI"&gt;Responsible AI in Vision&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href="https://portal.vision.cognitive.azure.com"&gt;Vision Studio&lt;/a&gt; to begin using features offered by the service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;For more information on the features offered, see the &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/cognitive-services/computer-vision/overview" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Computer Vision overview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/introducing-vision-studio-a-uibased-demo-interface-for-computer-vision/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/introducing-vision-studio-a-uibased-demo-interface-for-computer-vision/</link>
      <dc:creator>Kate Browne</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">azure-scales-530b-parameter-gpt3-model-with-nvidia-nemo-megatron</guid>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
      <category>Partner</category>
      <title>Azure Scales 530B Parameter GPT-3 Model with NVIDIA NeMo Megatron</title>
      <description>Combining NVIDIA NeMo Megatron with our Azure AI infrastructure offers a powerful platform that anyone can spin up in minutes without having to incur the costs and burden of managing their own on-premises infrastructure. And of course, we have taken our benchmarking of the new framework to a new level, to truly show the power of the Azure infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 09:00:37 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p style="border: currentcolor; border-image: none;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was co-authored by Hugo Affaticati, Technical Program Manager, Microsoft Azure HPC + AI, and Jon Shelley, Principal TPM Manager, Microsoft Azure HPC + AI.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="border: currentcolor; border-image: none;"&gt;Natural language processing (NLP), automated speech recognition (ASR), and text-to-speech (TTS) applications are becoming increasingly common in today&amp;rsquo;s world. Most companies have leveraged these technologies to create chatbots for managing customer questions and complaints, streamlining operations, and removing some of the heavy cost burden that comes with headcount. But what you may not realize is they&amp;rsquo;re also being used internally to reduce risk and identify fraudulent behavior, reduce customer complaints, increase automation, and analyze customer sentiment. It&amp;rsquo;s prevalent in most places, but especially in industries such as healthcare, finance, retail, and telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA recently released the latest version of the &lt;a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/nemo/megatron" target="_blank"&gt;NVIDIA NeMo Megatron&lt;/a&gt; framework, which is &lt;a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/nemo-megatron-open-beta" target="_blank"&gt;now in open beta&lt;/a&gt;. This framework can be used to build and deploy large language models (LLMs) with natural language understanding (NLU).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Combining NVIDIA NeMo Megatron with our &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com//free/ai/"&gt;Azure AI infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; offers a powerful platform that anyone can spin up in minutes without having to incur the costs and burden of managing their own on-premises infrastructure. And of course, we have taken our benchmarking of the new framework to a new level, to truly show the power of the Azure infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Reaching new milestones with 530B parameters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We used Azure NDm A100 v4-series virtual machines to run the GPT-3 model&amp;#39;s new NVIDIA NeMo Megatron framework and test the limits of this series. &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-machines/ndm-a100-v4-series" target="_blank"&gt;NDm A100 v4 virtual machines&lt;/a&gt; are Azure&amp;rsquo;s flagship GPU offerings for AI and deep learning powered by NVIDIA A100 80GB Tensor Core GPUs. These instances have the most GPU memory capacity and bandwidth, backed by NVIDIA InfiniBand HDR connections to support scaling up and out. Ultimately, &lt;strong&gt;we ran a 530B-parameter benchmark on 175 virtual machines, resulting in a training time per step of as low as 55.7 seconds&lt;/strong&gt; (figure1). This benchmark measures the compute efficiency and how it scales by measuring the time taken per step to train the model after steady state is reached, with a mini-batch size of one. Such outstanding speed would not have been possible without InfiniBand HDR providing excellent communication between nodes without increased latency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;figure class="image"&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/c6e5ee26-69a4-4967-b0a9-c85361dfc857.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="The graph shows Azure’s performance results on the GPT-3 530 billion-parameter model with NVIDIA NeMo Megatron. The Training time per step decreases almost linearly from 88.2 seconds to 55.8 seconds when the number of nodes increases from 105 to 175." border="0" height="559" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/74a401ab-b737-4144-a596-059842980bda.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Training time per step on the 530B-parameter benchmark from 105 to 175 virtual machines.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;These results highlight an almost linear speed increase, guaranteeing better performance for a higher number of nodes&amp;mdash;paramount for heavy or time-sensitive workloads. As shown by these runs with billions of parameters, customers can rest assured that Azure&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure can handle even the most difficult and complex workloads, on demand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Speed and scale are both key to developing large language models, and the latest release of the NVIDIA NeMo Megatron framework introduces new techniques to deliver 30 percent faster training for LLMs,&amp;rdquo; said Paresh Kharya, senior director of accelerated computing at NVIDIA. &amp;ldquo;Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s testing with NeMo Megatron 530B also shows that Azure NDm A100 v4 instances powered by NVIDIA A100 Tensor Core GPUs and NVIDIA InfiniBand networking provide a compelling option for achieving linear training speedups at massive scale.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Showcasing Azure AI capabilities&amp;mdash;now and in the future&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Azure&amp;rsquo;s commitment is to make AI and HPC accessible to everyone. It includes, but is not limited to, providing the best AI infrastructure that scales from the smallest use cases to the heaviest workloads. As we continue to innovate to build the best platform for your AI workloads, our promise to you is to use the latest benchmarks to test our AI capabilities. These results help drive our own innovation and showcase that there is no limit to what you can do. For all your AI computing needs, Azure has you covered.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the results or how to recreate them, please see the following links.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;A quick start guide to &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/azure-high-performance-computing/a-quick-start-guide-to-benchmarking-llm-models-in-azure-nvidia/ba-p/3655111" target="_blank"&gt;benchmarking LLM models in Azure: NVIDIA NeMo Megatron&amp;mdash;Results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;A quick start guide to &lt;a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/azure-high-performance-computing/a-quick-start-guide-to-benchmarking-llm-models-in-azure-nvidia/ba-p/3655124" target="_blank"&gt;benchmarking LLM models in Azure: NVIDIA NeMo Megatron&amp;mdash;Steps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azure-scales-530b-parameter-gpt3-model-with-nvidia-nemo-megatron/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/azure-scales-530b-parameter-gpt3-model-with-nvidia-nemo-megatron/</link>
      <dc:creator>Rachel Pruitt</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">networking-needs-simplified-with-azure-virtual-wan</guid>
      <category>Networking</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <title>Azure Virtual WAN simplifies networking needs</title>
      <description>Today we are excited to make announcements in multiple areas of Azure Virtual WAN (vWAN), a networking-as-a-service that brings networking, security, and routing functionalities together to provide a single operational interface.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 08:00:35 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today we are excited to make announcements in multiple areas of Azure Virtual WAN (vWAN), networking as a service that brings networking, security, and routing functionalities together to provide a single operational interface. As enterprises increasingly adopt the cloud while reducing their costs, IT teams looking to consolidate, accelerate, or even revamp their wide area network should consider Azure Virtual WAN. You don&amp;#39;t need to have all these use cases to start using Virtual WAN&amp;mdash;you can get started with just one. With ease of use and simplicity built in, vWAN is a one-stop shop to connect, protect, route traffic, and monitor your wide area network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Azure Virtual WAN is driving outcomes for Accenture. Migrating 250+ corporate networks to Virtual WAN with code-based deployments creates flexible, cheaper, and consistent networks for our customers. We can now easily connect new work sites in hours.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Conrad Johnson, Cloud Networks Service Director, Accenture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The following areas have key announcements:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Remote user connectivity (also known as point-to-site VPN).&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Routing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Branch connectivity (also known as site-to-site VPN).&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Private connectivity (also known as ExpressRoute).&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Third-Party Network Virtual Appliance Integrations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Remote-user connectivity (also known as point-to-site VPN)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Multipool user group support preview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Multipool user group support for remote-user (point-to-site) VPN allows you to assign different IP address pools to connecting users based on their credentials. With this feature, you can segment your remote users into distinct groups, assign each group unique IP addresses and use the assigned IPs to control and restrict access to business-critical applications hosted both in Azure and on-premises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;User groups within a Virtual WAN can be defined based on Azure Active Directory membership, Certificate Common Name domain or custom RADIUS attributes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/5a78e810-a345-43c1-b9ef-e25080ab8e9a.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="FigureA" border="0" height="522" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/5397c58b-bb38-47ad-8b3e-2a1e10b1ccbb.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="FigureA" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, Contoso corporation has three departments, human resources, finance, and engineering. Contoso also has an on-premises datacenter hosting several business applications connected to Virtual WAN via an ExpressRoute circuit. Contoso leverages Azure Active Directory groups and Virtual WAN remote user/point-to-site VPN groups to segment and assigns different IPs to HR, finance, and engineering users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Contoso then configures Azure Firewall and on-premises Firewall rules to allow each functional department to only access relevant applications. For example, Azure Firewall is configured to restrict access to applications in the HR VNet to HR Users. Likewise, on-premises firewalls are also configured to allow users access to applications based on need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;To learn more, read about the underlying &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/multipoolsconcept" target="_blank"&gt;concepts behind remote-user connectivity&lt;/a&gt; and watch a &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/multipoolstutorial" target="_blank"&gt;step-by-step tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id="Routing" name="Routing"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Routing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Secure hub routing intent preview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Routing intent and routing policies allow you to simplify securing your Azure Virtual WAN deployments. With a single click, you can send all traffic (including inter-region and branch-to-branch) to be inspected by Azure Firewall or select Next-Generation Firewall (NGFW) Network Virtual Appliances deployed in the virtual WAN hub. Virtual WAN&amp;rsquo;s router manages this all for you dynamically by using BGP so that you can avoid error-prone configurations.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/f6908866-a316-468d-a07d-41685b64121b.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="FigureBandC" border="0" height="334" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/651dc7a2-2104-43da-9a90-9ef4123c3c55.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="FigureBandC" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Configuring a routing policy on a hub makes that hub a regional security boundary&amp;mdash;all traffic entering or leaving that hub will be sent to Azure Firewall or NVA of choice for inspection before being forwarded to its destination. Routing policies allow you to deploy Azure Firewall/NVA as a bump-in-the-wire solution to inspect East-West (VNet-to-VNet, branch-to-branch (ExpressRoute, P2S VPN, S2S VPN), North-South (branch-to-VNet) traffic between resources connected to the same hub and different hubs. Azure Firewall or a Network virtual appliance Firewall can also serve as the egress point for internet traffic for Virtual Networks and on-premises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;For more information on how to use routing intent and policies, please see &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/how-to-routing-policies" target="_blank"&gt;how to configure Virtual WAN Hub routing policies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;For a list of available Next-Generation Firewall (NGFW) NVA&amp;rsquo;s deployed in the hub and appropriate instructions for deploying and accessing previews, please see our &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/about-nva-hub#partners" target="_blank"&gt;Network Virtual Appliances&lt;/a&gt; documentation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Hub routing preference (HRP) is generally available&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;When a virtual hub router learns multiple routes across S2S VPN, ER, and SD-WAN NVA connections for a destination route prefix on-premises, the virtual hub router makes routing decisions using a built-in route selection algorithm. Being able to select virtual hub routing preference provides the ability to influence routing decisions in a virtual hub router for traffic flowing towards on-premises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/6d3b5fb8-43f6-4209-a3e2-6ffbe1b5a096.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="FigureD" border="0" height="561" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/fb1a6525-bad6-4222-a9ec-53d1765564e6.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="FigureD" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Hub routing preference gives you more control over your infrastructure by allowing you to select how your traffic is routed when a virtual hub router learns multiple routes across S2S VPN, ER and SD-WAN NVA connections. Hub routing preference provides the ability to select between ExpressRoute, AS Path, and VPN to create your desired traffic flow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Routes are selected in the following order:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ol&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Select routes with Longest Prefix Match (LPM).&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Prefer static routes over BGP routes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Hub routing preference lets you select between ExpressRoute, AS Path, and VPN.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;For more information on hub routing preference, please see &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/about-virtual-hub-routing-preference" target="_blank"&gt;Virtual WAN virtual hub routing preference - Preview - Azure Virtual WAN | Microsoft Learn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Bypass next hop IP for workloads within a spoke VNet connected to the virtual WAN hub generally available&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;One of Virtual WANs most popular routing use cases is deploying an NVA in a spoke VNet attached to a virtual WAN hub, then routing traffic through the NVA. Bypassing next hop IP for workloads within a spoke VNet connected to the virtual WAN hub lets you deploy and access other resources in the VNet with your NVA without any additional configuration.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/658258d6-0167-40f8-8d5d-272b03b1ed78.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="FigureE" border="0" height="480" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/1ab3ada2-95e7-49a5-b497-ecf4e5aed1f6.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="FigureE" width="545"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Bypassing next hop IP for workloads within a spoke VNet connected to the virtual WAN hub allows you to have greater flexibility in how you deploy NVAs. This feature allows you to deploy NVAs and other workloads into the same VNet without forcing all the traffic through the NVA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/how-to-virtual-hub-routing" target="_blank"&gt;how to configure virtual hub routing&lt;/a&gt; and more about Bypass next hop IP for workloads within a spoke VNet connected to the virtual WAN hub.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) Peering with a virtual hub is generally available&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;BGP Peering with a virtual hub exposes the ability to peer with the virtual hub router directly using the Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) routing protocol. This feature now eliminates the need to configure static routes between a Network Virtual Appliance (NVA) and the virtual hub router.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;BGP Peering with a virtual hub enables you to deploy an NVA in a spoke VNet and dynamically exchange routes with your branch and on-premises sites. You can then peer that same NVA with the virtual hub dynamically using BGP. Now you can exchange routes between your branch and the virtual hub without using static routes!&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Read more &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/scenario-bgp-peering-hub" target="_blank"&gt;about BGP peering with a virtual hub &lt;/a&gt;on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/create-bgp-peering-hub-portal" target="_blank"&gt;configure BGP peering to an NVA virtual hub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Branch connectivity (also known as site-to-site VPN)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;BGP dashboard is now generally available&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The BGP dashboard provides the ability to monitor BGP peers, advertised routes, and learned routes for your site-to-site VPNs configured to use BGP in one place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/f94a8193-583f-4c2e-81fb-cfe4e4984b98.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Figure G" border="0" height="576" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/9e5c465b-1b33-4bde-a4a3-f4c6a4df5f67.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="Figure G" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The BGP dashboard provides greater visibility into your branch offices connected to Virtual WAN. You now have the ability to see what routes your branch office is sending to the virtual WAN router, while also seeing what routes the Virtual WAN router is sending to your branch offices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;See more information on how to &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/monitor-bgp-dashboard" target="_blank"&gt;monitor S2S VPN BGP routes&lt;/a&gt; on the BGP dashboard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;For customers that want to use a non-vWAN VPN gateway, also known as a Virtual Network gateway, which can be used to set up a site-to-site connection within Azure to a Virtual WAN system, the following Virtual WAN&amp;ndash;enabled capabilities are worth checking out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Virtual Network Gateway VPN over ExpressRoute private peering (AZ and non-AZ regions) is generally available&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Customers can now use VPN over ExpressRoute private peering connectivity in non-AZ regions. Earlier, this feature was only available for regions having availability zones. The following gateway SKUs can be used for setting up VPN connectivity:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;VpnGw1/2/3/4/5 SKUs with standard public IP for regions with no availability zones&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;VpnGw1AZ/2AZ3AZ/4AZ/5AZ SKUs with standard public IP for regions having one or more availability zones&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Point-to-site users connecting to a virtual network gateway can use ExpressRoute (via the site-to-site tunnel) to access on-premises resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Customers can deploy site-to-site VPN connections over ExpressRoute private peering at the same time as site-to-site VPN connection via the Internet on the same VPN gateway.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/vpn-gateway/site-to-site-vpn-private-peering?toc=/azure/expressroute/toc.json" target="_blank"&gt;more information on this new feature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Custom traffic selectors (portal)&amp;ndash;generally available&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Customers may want to set traffic selectors to narrow down address prefixes from both ends of a VPN tunnel. Custom traffic selectors are particularly useful for customers who have large VNet address spaces but want to use one of their subnets for IPsec/IKE negotiation. Customers can add custom traffic selectors when creating a new connection or update an existing connection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we enabled custom traffic selectors using PowerShell. Customers can now also use the portal to set custom traffic selectors on their Virtual Network Gateway VPN connections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;TrafficSelectorPolicy&lt;/em&gt; parameter consists of an array of traffic selectors, with each traffic selector holding a collection of local and remote address ranges in CIDR format.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;See more information on &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/vpn-gateway/tutorial-site-to-site-portal#configure-connect" target="_blank"&gt;setting up traffic selectors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;High availability for Azure VPN client using secondary profile is generally available&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Customers can now use Azure VPN client in Windows to add a secondary gateway preference in their primary gateway configuration. This feature improves connection availability for point-to-site customers by having a pre-configured additional profile. If for some reason, the primary gateway encounters an outage, VPN client will automatically failover to connect with the secondary gateway.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/7f134e8c-fad9-4288-9240-edc8db2c8531.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="FigureJ" border="0" height="480" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/53c6e012-c579-408c-91f0-2c91706ba94a.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="FigureJ" width="594"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;See more information on &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/vpn-gateway/point-to-site-vpn-client-cert-windows#configure-the-vpn-client-profile" target="_blank"&gt;Azure VPN client using secondary profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Private connectivity (also known as ExpressRoute)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;ExpressRoute circuit with visibility of Virtual WAN connection&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Previously in Azure Portal, when navigating to an ExpressRoute circuit connected to a Virtual WAN hub, the ExpressRoute circuit&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Connections &lt;/strong&gt;page did not display the connections to the virtual hub&amp;rsquo;s ExpressRoute gateway. With this feature, these connections to the virtual hub&amp;rsquo;s ExpressRoute gateways are now visible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;By displaying these connections to the ExpressRoute gateways in the virtual hub, this feature provides you with more visibility into your Azure architecture. Not only does this enable you to gain a deeper understanding of your topology, but this will allow you to better monitor and troubleshoot your ExpressRoute connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Watch a tutorial on how to &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/virtual-wan-expressroute-portal" target="_blank"&gt;create an ExpressRoute association to Azure Virtual WAN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Third-party integrations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Fortinet SDWAN is generally available&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the general availability of Fortinet SD-WAN in Virtual WAN. Fortinet&amp;rsquo;s security-driven approach consolidates next-generation Azure Firewall and SD-WAN into a single set of hassle-free solutions to deploy and bootstrap highly available virtual appliances and provide full security inspection at the point of cloud connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Fortinet SD-WAN dynamically exchanges routes with the Virtual Hub Router using BGP to effortlessly simplify routing between Fortinet SD-WAN branch devices, your applications hosted in Azure Virtual Networks, and services hosted on ExpressRoute-connected on-premises.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/35b7ae09-c9b5-4e05-b7c5-cc8c0093f51f.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="FigureL" border="0" height="540" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/6d93e050-d382-48c9-8d64-cc7417b62c6f.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="FigureL" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Find more information &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/about-nva-hub" target="_blank"&gt;about Network Virtual Appliances in Virtual WAN&lt;/a&gt; on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Read more about &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/fortinetsdwandeploy" target="_blank"&gt;Fortinet SD-WAN in Virtual WAN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Aruba EdgeConnect Enterprise SDWAN preview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the preview of Aruba EdgeConnect Enterprise SD-WAN solution in Azure Virtual WAN. The Aruba EdgeConnect Enterprise SD-WAN solution delivers optimized, secured, and automated branch connectivity to, and through, Azure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/95ebadca-c0a2-4694-9e24-2170a329c3fc.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="FigureN" border="0" height="668" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/4146ed1c-2af3-4a6e-abef-911ecb907968.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="FigureN" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The Aruba EdgeConnect Enterprise solution provides a fully-automated, scalable, and software-defined experience connecting branch offices and data centers to Azure Virtual WAN with application-aware traffic steering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;See more on &lt;a href="https://www.arubanetworks.com/techdocs/sdwan/media/deployments/dg_ECV-Azure-VWAN_latest.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;how to deploy the Aruba EdgeConnect Enterprise SD-WAN in Virtual WAN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Read about &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/about-nva-hub" target="_blank"&gt;Integrated Network Virtual Appliances in Virtual WAN&lt;/a&gt; on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Checkpoint NG Firewall preview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the preview of Check Point&amp;rsquo;s Next-Generation Firewall in Virtual WAN. This deep integration allows you to deploy a Check Point Cloud Guard Network Security (CGNS) NVA in the Virtual WAN hub, which lets you enjoy Check Point capabilities without having to worry about provisioning high availability, bootstrapping, or managing upgrades. A major benefit of this NVA integration is simplified routing, as the NVA peers use BGP with the Virtual WAN hub router, which intelligently handles routing decisions within and across Virtual WAN hubs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Check Point CGNS provides many next-generation firewall capabilities, such as advanced threat detection to prevent malware attacks. In addition, you can configure Check Point security policies via a single pane of glass with &lt;a href="https://www.checkpoint.com/quantum/unified-cyber-security-platform/" target="_blank"&gt;Check Point Security Management&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jWntIAFKWGk" target="_blank"&gt;Watch a demo&lt;/a&gt; on this integration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Read more about the &lt;a href="https://blog.checkpoint.com/2022/08/02/check-point-announces-its-azure-virtual-wan-security-solution/" target="_blank"&gt;Check Point Azure Virtual WAN security solution&lt;/a&gt; announcement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Find more information &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/about-nva-hub" target="_blank"&gt;about Integrated Network Virtual Appliances&lt;/a&gt; on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;We want your feedback&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to continuing to build out Azure Virtual WAN and adding more capabilities in the future. We encourage you to try out Azure Virtual WAN and its new features and look forward to hearing more about your experiences and so we can incorporate your feedback into the product.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;For additional information, please explore these resources:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/virtual-wan/whats-new" target="_blank"&gt;What&amp;#39;s new in Azure Virtual WAN?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://aka.ms\vwandocs" target="_blank"&gt;Virtual WAN documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;hr&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1. Support for inter-region traffic inspection is currently rolling out and is available today for a limited set of regions. To learn more, please reach out to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:previewinterhub@microsoft.com"&gt;&lt;em&gt;previewinterhub@microsoft.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2. NGFW use cases for Routing Intent are currently in preview. Please see &lt;a href="#Routing"&gt;Routing Intent&lt;/a&gt; section above for more details.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/networking-needs-simplified-with-azure-virtual-wan/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/networking-needs-simplified-with-azure-virtual-wan/</link>
      <dc:creator>Reshmi Yandapalli</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">visualize-and-monitor-azure-hybrid-networks-with-azure-network-watcher</guid>
      <category>Networking</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <category>Monitoring</category>
      <title>Visualize and monitor Azure &amp; hybrid networks with Azure Network Watcher</title>
      <description>Network Watcher helps customers monitor, manage, and understand their own networks for performance, connectivity, security, and compliance issues and furthermore, empowers customers to troubleshoot efficiently with actionable insights and proactive alerting, thus effectively reducing the mean time to resolve network issues.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 08:00:20 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There is a critical need for increased visibility and control over the operational state of complex networks running sophisticated workloads. Multi-cloud and hybrid network environments power new demands of remote work, 5G/Edge connectivity, microservices based workloads, and increased cloud adoption. The advent of the cloud has added agility, cost benefits, and brought along the need for management of the infrastructure. Management and monitoring of the network underlying these complex applications plays a key role in ensuring end-user satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ms.portal.azure.com/#view/Microsoft_Azure_Network/NetworkWatcherMenuBlade/~/overview" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Network Watcher&lt;/a&gt; provides an entire suite of tools to visualize, monitor, diagnose, and troubleshoot network issues across Azure and Hybrid cloud environments. Network Watcher enables customers to detect anomalies across Azure and hybrid networks with comprehensive wide coverage, through a guided and intuitive drilled-down experience. Network Watcher helps customers monitor, manage, and understand their own networks for performance, connectivity, security, and compliance issues and furthermore, empowers customers to troubleshoot efficiently with actionable insights and proactive alerting, thus effectively reducing the mean time to resolve network issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/2cc950b1-be67-46e9-9748-6ec1080437e9.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A screenshot displaying a topology of connectivity test created from on-premises ARC enabled machine with Azure Monitor Agent enabled , with packet loss and RTT metrics." border="0" height="521" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/ab8a0431-8c31-4667-a555-cd27d1d31464.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The following new feature enhancements across Network Watcher suite aim to provide timely and complete visibility and actionable insights to customers of their hybrid networks in a manner that is easily accessible, readily usable, and reliable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Visualize resource and network health with Topology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Topology enables users to quickly acquire system context, comprehend state, and troubleshoot issues efficiently by visualizing the resources in a network. It offers a visually connected experience for monitoring and managing inventory.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This new topology experience in Azure, which replaces the Network Watcher topology, will enable customers to create a consistent and dynamic topology across multiple subscriptions, regions, and resource groups (RGs)&amp;mdash;comprising of numerous resources.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/fb66b340-dab1-4a5d-bf51-69fb01f9071f.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A screenshot showing Azure Resource Topology visualization." border="0" height="553" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/c7d7ad0e-a7ef-4fa2-9aaf-e9825f45d91b.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Allowing deep dives into the customer&amp;rsquo;s environment, Topology lets users drill down from regions, VNETs to subnets, and resource view diagram of resources supported in Azure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Stitching the end-to-end monitoring and diagnostics story for all Network Monitoring needs, topology offers the capability to run Next Hop directly from a VM selected in the topology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Significant features available with this preview: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Multi-region and multi-subscription&amp;ndash;dynamic drill-down visualization.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Health status of resources using resource health (RHC) status.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Diagnostics tool Next Hop integration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Resource view diagram for all supported resources.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Monitor connectivity using Azure Monitor Agent with Connection Monitor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Integration of Azure Monitor Agent&amp;rsquo;s support consolidates multi-monitoring agents into a single connectivity monitoring agent in Azure Network Watcher&amp;rsquo;s Connection Monitor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Connection Monitor, a multi-agent solution, monitors connectivity at regular intervals across Azure and Hybrid endpoints and provides aggregated data for packet loss, latency, and status codes over TCP, ICMP, and HTTP(s) pings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/2a83c79a-3c3d-4a33-8322-969c38b1e55c.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A screenshot of Network Watcher portfolio, displaying end to end network monitoring and management with Network Watcher suite." border="0" height="596" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/30bab5e7-74dc-4609-b435-c8cdff39a6c3.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Connection Monitor helps you troubleshoot network issues with faster alerts for lack of connectivity or reachability to the endpoints. The unified topology rendered provides a complete end-to-end visualization of the network path from source to destination, with actionable insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This agent integration enhancement addresses connectivity monitoring logs and metrics data collection needs across Azure and ARC-enabled on-premises machines, thus eliminating the overhead of management and enablement of multiple monitoring agents. Additionally, Azure Monitor Agent provides enhanced security and performance capabilities, effective cost savings, and ease of troubleshooting with simpler management of data collection. With this support, dependency on the soon-to-be-retired&lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/updates/were-retiring-the-log-analytics-agent-in-azure-monitor-on-31-august-2024/" target="_blank"&gt; Log Analytics agent&lt;/a&gt; is eliminated, while increasing the coverage for on-premises machines with support for ARC-enabled endpoints.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Significant features available with preview:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Connectivity monitoring support for ARC-enabled on-premises endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Simpler management of monitoring extension.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;One agent for monitoring Azure and non-Azure endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Enhanced security through Managed Identity and Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tokens.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn More&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Please navigate to the &lt;a href="https://ms.portal.azure.com/#view/Microsoft_Azure_Monitoring/AzureMonitoringBrowseBlade/~/networkInsights" target="_blank"&gt;Network Insights portal&lt;/a&gt; to try out Azure Topology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Refer here to learn more about &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/network-watcher/network-insights-overview" target="_blank"&gt;Network Insights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Please navigate to the &lt;a href="https://ms.portal.azure.com/#view/Microsoft_Azure_Network/NetworkWatcherMenuBlade/~/connectionMonitor" target="_blank"&gt;Connection Monitor portal&lt;/a&gt; to try out Connection Monitor with Azure Monitor Agent.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Refer here to learn more about &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/network-watcher/connection-monitor-overview" target="_blank"&gt;Connection Monitor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/visualize-and-monitor-azure-hybrid-networks-with-azure-network-watcher/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/visualize-and-monitor-azure-hybrid-networks-with-azure-network-watcher/</link>
      <dc:creator>Medhashree Jha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">announcing-azure-dns-private-resolver-general-availability</guid>
      <category>Networking</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <category>DevOps</category>
      <title>Announcing Azure DNS Private Resolver general availability</title>
      <description>We are excited to share that Azure DNS Private Resolver is now in general availability. We offer two types of Azure DNS Zones—private and public—for hosting your private DNS and public DNS records.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 08:00:05 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A successful hybrid networking strategy demands DNS services that work seamlessly across on-premises and cloud networks. Azure DNS Private Resolver now provides a fully managed recursive resolution and conditional forwarding service for &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/free/virtual-network"&gt;Azure virtual networks&lt;/a&gt;. Using this service, you will be able to resolve DNS names hosted in Azure DNS private zones from on-premises networks as well as DNS queries originating from Azure virtual networks that can be forwarded to a specified destination server to resolve them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This service will provide a highly available and resilient DNS infrastructure on Azure for a fraction of the price of running traditional IaaS VMs running DNS servers in virtual networks. You will be able to seamlessly integrate with Private DNS Zones and unlock key scenarios with minimal operational overhead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to share that Azure DNS Private Resolver is now in general availability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;A quick overview of Azure DNS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/aaed4ba6-53e8-48e5-9c34-2c387352e0c5.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A flow diagram of multi-region workloads running on Azure with DNS Private Resolver provisioned in two regional, centralized workloads." border="0" height="715" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/fad007b7-17d2-44f1-b49b-671ac5678e50.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We offer two types of Azure DNS Zones&amp;mdash;private and public&amp;mdash;for hosting your private DNS and public DNS records. In the preceding illustration, multi-region workloads running on Azure with Azure DNS Private Resolver are provisioned in two regional, centralized virtual networks with one or more spokes peered to each centralized virtual network. These virtual networks have inbound and outbound endpoints provisioned. From on-premises, there are two distinct locations (East and West) and each location connects via Express Route to the centralized virtual network where Private Resolver is provisioned. These on-premises locations have one or more local DNS servers configured to do conditional forwarding to the inbound endpoint of Private Resolver. The local DNS servers in East have the IP address of the East inbound endpoint as the primary DNS target, and the West inbound endpoint as secondary. Alternatively, the local DNS servers in West have the IP address of the West inbound endpoint as the primary DNS target, and the East inbound endpoint&amp;nbsp;as secondary. There is a single private DNS zone linked to both regions and both on-premises locations can resolve names from this zone even in the event of a regional failure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/dns/private-dns-overview" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Private DNS&lt;/a&gt;: Azure Private DNS provides a reliable and secure DNS service for your virtual network. Azure Private DNS manages and resolves domain names in the virtual network without the need to configure a custom DNS solution. By using private DNS zones, you can use your own custom domain name instead of the Azure-provided names during deployment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/dns/dns-overview" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Public DNS&lt;/a&gt;: DNS domains in Azure DNS are hosted on Azure&amp;#39;s global network of DNS name servers. Azure DNS uses anycast networking. Each DNS query is answered by the closest available DNS server to provide fast performance and high availability for your domain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;What is being announced today?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Azure DNS Private Resolver&lt;/strong&gt; enables you to query Azure DNS private zones from an on-premises environment and vice versa without deploying virtual machine-based DNS servers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Azure DNS Private Resolver&lt;/strong&gt; general availability is being announced to all customers and will have regional availability in the following regions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="0"&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;
		&lt;tr&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;East US&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;East US 2&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Central US&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;South Central US&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;North Central US&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;West Central US&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;West US 3&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Canada Central&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Brazil South&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;West Europe&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;North Europe&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;UK South&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;France Central&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Sweden Central&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Switzerland North&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;td valign="top"&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;East Asia&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Southeast Asia&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Japan East&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Korea Central&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;South Africa North&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;li&gt;Australia East&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
				&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
			&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;
		&lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;What will customers be able to do with Azure Private Resolver?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the features which were announced earlier in preview, customers will now be able to leverage the following additional functionality and content:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Additional &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/dns/tutorial-dns-private-resolver-failover" target="_blank"&gt;architectural guidance for higher resiliency and enabling disaster recovery scenarios&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;In-depth information on &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/dns/private-resolver-endpoints-rulesets" target="_blank"&gt;how to configure conditional forwarding rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Configuring &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/dns/private-resolver-hybrid-dns" target="_blank"&gt;hybrid name resolution from on-premises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In the following diagram, an on-premises network connects to Azure via ExpressRoute and has on-premises DNS servers configured to conditionally forward queries to the private IP address of the inbound endpoint. The inbound endpoint then resolves names available on Azure Private DNS zones which are linked to the virtual network where private resolver is provisioned. If there is no matching private DNS zone in the virtual network, it will use the outbound endpoint and resolve using the ruleset rules via longest suffix match. If no match in the ruleset is found it will recurse to the internet for public name resolution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/318092f2-5399-4854-be43-745a95820e2b.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A diagram showing an on-premises network connected to Azure via ExpressRoute forwarding queries to the private IP address of the inbound endpoint. The inbound endpoint then resolves names available on Azure Private DNS zones. " border="0" height="768" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/2c9ecb23-1da4-4602-bc54-c5c49f04065c.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="729"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Features and benefits&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Cross-subscription support to link virtual networks from different subscriptions to rulesets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Resource Health Check Integration to provide visibility of endpoint health to our customers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/15bbfde4-57ce-4484-b876-6bee7755b37b.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Alert condition for resource health check can be configured in the Portal and allows to select resource status on which you’d like to receive alerts such as: available, degraded, and unavailable." border="0" height="168" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/7dae8df1-b1d4-4538-ab5a-9334d6833c0d.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="400"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/3354d99a-64f6-4a40-91d3-902fd3acd7e5.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="TBD." border="0" height="86" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/8c30da38-a458-4965-a73a-cafcd724ddb9.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="400"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Visibility of query metrics per endpoint to plan for future capacity:&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/85f01eef-de2d-4907-aafb-8413b9f947f1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Query metrics per endpoint are shown in a bar graph." border="0" height="180" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/629fc606-9557-4b03-b4e0-0616b42b0df3.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="400"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;PrivateLink enabled services integration in conditional forwarding to exclude Azure infra zones from being resolved on-premises.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Private Resolver general availability is also available to use via PowerShell, CLI, .NET, Java, Python, REST, Typescript, Go, ARM, and Terraform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Key use cases for this service&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Conditionally forward from on-premises with Azure ExpressRoute/VPN and resolve names hosted on Azure Private DNS Zones via private IP address.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Seamlessly resolve Private Endpoints which are registered in Azure Private DNS Zones.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Configure default DNS servers and forward all DNS queries to either a Protective DNS service or other target DNS servers with a wildcard rule.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Conditionally forward to any reachable target DNS server using a simple rule.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;Access resources on-premises with Azure Bastion using names hosted on DNS servers on-premises or Azure Private DNS zones.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Fully managed&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in high availability, zone redundancy, and low latency name resolution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Reduces cost&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Reduce operating costs and run at a fraction of the price of traditional IaaS solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Private access to your Private DNS Zones&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Conditionally forward from your Virtual Networks to any reachable DNS server and from on-premises to Azure Private DNS Zones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Scalability&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;High performance per endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;Highly available&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Availability Zone aware and resilient to failures within a region. Service-legal agreement (SLA) of 99.99 percent during general availability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h3&gt;DevOps-friendly&lt;/h3&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Build your pipelines with Terraform, ARM, or Bicep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Get started and share your feedback&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;You can try Azure DNS Private Resolver today. For more information about the capabilities available, please visit the &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/azure/dns/dns-private-resolver-overview" target="_blank"&gt;Azure DNS Private Resolver&lt;/a&gt; technical documentation webpage. Post your ideas and suggestions on the &lt;a href="https://feedback.azure.com/d365community/forum/8ae9bf04-8326-ec11-b6e6-000d3a4f0789"&gt;networking community page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/announcing-azure-dns-private-resolver-general-availability/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/announcing-azure-dns-private-resolver-general-availability/</link>
      <dc:creator>Sergio Figueiredo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">elevate-your-visualizations-with-azure-managed-grafana-now-generally-available</guid>
      <category>Big Data</category>
      <category>Management</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <category>DevOps</category>
      <title>Elevate your visualizations with Azure Managed Grafana—now generally available</title>
      <description>Announcing the general availability of Azure Managed Grafana, a managed service that enables you to run Grafana natively within the Azure cloud platform. With Azure Managed Grafana, you can seamlessly and securely connect with and scale to businesses’ existing Azure services, enhancing observability and cloud management.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 11:00:01 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As part of our continued commitment to open source solutions, we are announcing the general availability of &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/managed-grafana/" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Managed Grafana&lt;/a&gt;, a managed service that enables you to run Grafana natively within the Azure cloud platform. With Azure Managed Grafana, you can seamlessly and securely connect with and scale to businesses&amp;rsquo; existing Azure services, enhancing observability and cloud management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the features &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/enhance-your-data-visualizations-with-azure-managed-grafana-now-in-preview/" target="_blank"&gt;announced during preview&lt;/a&gt;, with general availability, we&amp;rsquo;re introducing new capabilities that include the latest Grafana v9.0 features with its improved alerting experience as well as zone redundancy (in preview) and API key support.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;New connections and integrations with Azure services&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;With general availability, we are adding new integrations with Azure services, allowing you to realize the benefits of Grafana as efficiently and effectively as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We have introduced several new out-of-the-box dashboards for &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/monitor/" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Monitor&lt;/a&gt;. For example, with &lt;strong&gt;Availability Tests Geo Map dashboard for Azure Monitor application insights&lt;/strong&gt;, you can view the results and responsiveness of your application availability tests based on geographic location. Additionally, with the new out-of-the-box &lt;strong&gt;Load Balancing dashboard for Azure Monitor network insights&lt;/strong&gt;, you can monitor key performance metrics for all your Azure load balancing resources, including Load Balancers, Application Gateway, Front Door, and Traffic Manager.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/6036265d-947a-4d47-8d83-0088912809f5.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A dashboard on a black background. In the center-left is a world map with translucent red and green dots on it. On the far right are 2 graphs, one line graph and another semi circular one." border="0" height="576" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/958542b2-fcfb-41cc-b201-369b5c215181.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/c779b6b7-fb25-4d07-8d0c-ed23bb3ce1eb.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A dashboard on a black background. There are 4 line graphs (in green) across the center of the page." border="0" height="575" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/b38371a5-46f6-4544-be41-651d0692278c.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;pin to Grafana&amp;rdquo; feature for Azure Monitor Logs&lt;/strong&gt; allows you to seamlessly add charts and queries from Azure Monitor Logs to Grafana dashboards with just one click. In the illustration below, you can see how the Azure Monitor Logs query on the left is replicated in the Grafana interface on the right.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/1110eb60-f700-41cb-9510-7c5c981ad3d1.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="179391_image 4a" height="260" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/104bdfd8-78ba-4640-9713-43d9be8d07e8.png" style="display: inline;" title="179391_image 4a" width="400"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/fb8d3021-0086-4bf5-a64b-2bfeb52a9917.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="179391_image 4b" height="268" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/3af89da2-f4a5-4466-a47a-b388ee0b4fcb.png" style="display: inline;" title="179391_image 4b" width="400"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, we have introduced new out-of-the-box dashboards for &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/container-apps/" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Container Apps&lt;/a&gt; as well. The new &lt;strong&gt;Aggregate View dashboard for Azure Container Apps&lt;/strong&gt; depicts a geographic map of your container apps filtered by resource group, environment, and region with drill-down links to a detailed dashboard for each app. The new &lt;strong&gt;App View dashboard for Azure Container Apps&lt;/strong&gt; monitors the performance of Azure Container Apps by viewing the key metrics of CPU, memory, restarts, and network traffic or by revision, replica, and status code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/98170a27-0bb6-4076-b9d9-d9281bd68f1a.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="A dashboard on a black background. There are 6 line graphs in this view, all capturing different metrics of container app." border="0" height="576" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/5a8ff275-8459-4810-ab7a-025d3c06a852.png" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/AMGtechcommunityblogGA" target="_blank"&gt;Azure Managed Grafana technical community blog&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the latest enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Get started with Azure Managed Grafana&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Try it free for the first 30 days from the &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/get-started/azure-portal/" target="_blank"&gt;Azure portal&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the Azure Managed Grafana &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/azuremanagedgrafanaACOM" target="_blank"&gt;product page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/managed-grafana/" target="_blank"&gt;technical documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Share feedback on &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/azuremanagedgrafanaQnA" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/elevate-your-visualizations-with-azure-managed-grafana-now-generally-available/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/elevate-your-visualizations-with-azure-managed-grafana-now-generally-available/</link>
      <dc:creator>Arti Gulwadi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid
        isPermaLink="false">announcing-new-enhancements-for-azure-vmware-solution</guid>
      <category>Virtual Machines</category>
      <category>Updates</category>
      <title>Announcing new enhancements for Azure VMware Solution</title>
      <description>When we launched Azure VMware Solution two years ago amid a pandemic, IT agility became a top priority as organizations scrambled to enable remote work and ensure business resilience via cloud solutions. Fast forward to today, and most organizations recognize that by running workloads in the cloud, they can respond more rapidly, no matter what the challenge or opportunity.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 05:00:03 Z</pubDate>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to be writing to you today from VMware Explore in San Francisco, where my team and I will be presenting and meeting with customers and partners in person! When we launched &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/azure-vmware/"&gt;Azure VMware Solution&lt;/a&gt; two years ago amid a pandemic, IT agility became a top priority as organizations scrambled to enable remote work and ensure business resilience via cloud solutions. Fast forward to today, and most organizations recognize that by running workloads in the cloud, they can respond more rapidly, no matter what the challenge or opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s much easier for us to take on smaller acquisitions and bring them onboard &amp;hellip; by using Azure VMware Solution, we&amp;rsquo;re always ready and able to add a node and start folding in the new acquisition&amp;rsquo;s applications and data with the extra capacity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;Dean Hughes, Infrastructure Manager, &lt;a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/story/1508875931123061701-carpetright-retailers-azure" target="_blank"&gt;Carpetright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ordering and installing on-premises networking hosts can take six months. But using Azure VMware Solution, it&amp;rsquo;s a simple process to run up new hosts that we can have working in a few days.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;Harry Sturgess, Manager of Technology and Operations, &lt;a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/story/1503899547462355298-metro-south-health-provider-azure-vmware-solution" target="_blank"&gt;Metro South Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Because every customer starts their cloud journey at a different place, we help enable customers to migrate to the cloud on their terms and maintain support for the business platforms and investments they have today. Azure VMware Solution is an easy way to extend and migrate existing VMware Private Clouds to run them natively on Azure. Azure VMware Solution offers symmetry with on-premises environments, which helps to accelerate datacenter migrations, so customers recognize the benefits of the cloud sooner. This symmetry also allows IT teams to leverage the same VMware skills, processes, and investments from their on-premises VMware environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What a game-changer for us. As a VMware house, we saw how easy it would be to move applications from VMware to Azure VMware Solution because it&amp;rsquo;s bolted onto the back of Azure.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;mdash;Rob Wilde, Platforms Manager, &lt;a href="https://customers.microsoft.com/story/1477034973006130434-nottinghamshire-county-council-government-azure-vmware-solution" target="_blank"&gt;Nottinghamshire County Council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s unique Azure Hybrid Benefit and Extended Security Updates for Windows Server and SQL Server, Azure VMware Solution is one of the fastest and most cost-effective ways to seamlessly migrate and run VMware in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Option coming for VMware Cloud Universal Program&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Today we extended our partnership with VMware to add support for the VMware Cloud Universal program. This will allow customers to purchase Azure VMware Solution as part of VMware Cloud Universal program, a flexible purchasing and consumption program for executing hybrid and multi-cloud strategies. With VMware Cloud Universal, customers may purchase credits for VMware&amp;rsquo;s multi-cloud infrastructure and management and apply these credits to deployments of Azure VMware Solution. &lt;a href="https://news.vmware.com/releases/azure-vmware-solution-vmware-cloud-universal"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Check out what&amp;rsquo;s new in Azure VMware Solution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Today I am excited to share some of the recent updates we&amp;rsquo;ve made to Azure VMware Solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global expansion to 24 regions:&lt;/strong&gt; Since the launch of Azure VMware Solution two years ago, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working to support customers globally with geographic expansion to 24 Azure regions, more than any other cloud provider. Check out the &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/global-infrastructure/services/?products=azure-vmware" target="_blank"&gt;Azure products by region&lt;/a&gt; web page to find a region near you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 40px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/79cc6e1b-24a0-447a-b1f3-8dd413ecb6f1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="A world map showing Azure product region locations such as Central US, East US, North Europe and so on." border="0" height="576" src="https://azurecomcdn.azureedge.net/mediahandler/acomblog/media/Default/blog/97468ad2-bc71-4e07-9bb9-0b81c6da4f84.jpg" style="border: 0px currentcolor; border-image: none; display: inline; background-image: none;" title="" width="1024"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Azure NetApp Files datastores for Azure VMware Solution&lt;/strong&gt; is now in public preview. For your storage-intensive workloads running on Azure VMware Solution, the integration with Azure NetApp Files helps to easily scale storage capacity beyond the limits of the local instance storage provided by vSAN and lower your overall total cost of ownership for storage-intensive workloads. &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/public-preview-azure-netapp-files-datastores-for-azure-vmware-solution-public-preview-2-2/" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public IP to NSX Edge capability for Azure VMware Solution&lt;/strong&gt; is now generally available in 17 Azure regions. Most customer applications running on Azure VMware Solution require internet access requiring both outbound and inbound internet connectivity. With this new capability, there are now three primary patterns for creating inbound and outbound internet access to resources on your Azure VMware Solution private cloud. &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/generally-available-public-ip-capability-for-azure-vmware-solution/" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise VMware Cloud Director Services for Azure VMware Solution is now in Public Preview.&lt;/strong&gt; Customers who have Azure VMware Solution deployed under their Microsoft Enterprise agreement can purchase the VMware Cloud Director Service from VMware and connect their Azure VMware Solution private cloud to create and manage private virtual datacenters and leverage vCloud availability for migrating on-premises VMware workloads to Azure VMware Solution private clouds. &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-vmware/enable-vmware-cds-with-azure" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jetstream DR for Azure VMware Solution &lt;/strong&gt;is now generally available, providing customers with disaster recovery protection needed for business and mission-critical applications while leveraging cost-effective cloud storage such as Azure Blob Storage. JetStream DR can also replicate and automate recovery to Azure NetApp Files datastores. &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/generally-available-jetstream-disaster-recovery-for-azure-vmware-solution-now-supports-azure-netapp-files-datastores/" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VMware vRealize Log Insight Cloud for Azure VMware Solution is now generally available.&lt;/strong&gt; This service provides centralized log management, deep operational visibility, intelligent analytics, and improved troubleshooting and security. This boosts IT organizations&amp;rsquo; operational efficiency, mitigates costs arising from unplanned downtime, and reduces organizational risk by providing visibility into security-related events. &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/generally-available-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-with-azure-vmware-solution-integration/" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VMware vSphere 7.0&lt;/strong&gt; is now available globally for all cloud deployments in Azure VMware Solution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to stay up to date with the latest releases from Azure VMware Solution, please follow &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/generally-available-vrealize-log-insight-cloud-with-azure-vmware-solution-integration/" target="_blank"&gt;Azure updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This week we are offering a special opportunity to take the Azure VMware Solution Cloud Skills Challenge. Compete in this free, self-paced, Microsoft learning path and advance your technical skills at the same time! &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/challenges?id=2ddcc4df-31fb-477a-8ee7-8f5e4da74288" target="_blank"&gt;Register for the Challenge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;As always, you can visit the &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/services/azure-vmware/"&gt;Azure VMware Solution website&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-vmware/" target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;And if you are here at VMware Explore, stop by the Microsoft booth and say hello. We are excited to see you in person! Booth #1101.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;hr&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;VMware vCloud, vRealize, and vSphere are registered trademarks of VMware, Inc. or its subsidiaries in the United States and other jurisdictions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
</content:encoded>
      <comments>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/announcing-new-enhancements-for-azure-vmware-solution/#comments</comments>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/blog/announcing-new-enhancements-for-azure-vmware-solution/</link>
      <dc:creator>Ram Gowrishankar</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>