<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss xmlns:a10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Azure service updates</title><link>https://www.microsoft.com/releasecommunications/api/v2/Azure/rss</link><description>Azure service updates</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 20:30:17 Z</lastBuildDate><ttl>1440</ttl><item><guid isPermaLink="false">491990</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=491990</link><category>In preview</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>API Management</category><category>Microsoft Build</category><category>Features</category><title>[In preview] Generally Available: Model Context Protocol support in Azure API Management and Azure API Center </title><description>Announcing
the public preview of Model Context Protocol (MCP) support in Azure API
Management and Azure API Center. With this new capability, enterprises can
transform their existing APIs into dynamic, agent-ready tools, while improving
security and simpl</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 15:00:30 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-25T20:30:17Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">534482</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=534482</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Networking</category><category>Network Watcher</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Managed Identity support in Network Watcher VNET flow log, traffic analytics and packet capture</title><description>VNET flow log captures IP
traffic flowing through VNETs, subnets, and NICs for monitoring, troubleshooting,
network optimization, security, and compliance needs and stores the logs in Azure
Storage Traffic Analytics leverages
VNET flow logs and aggregates</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:45:50 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-25T16:45:50Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">534541</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=534541</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Claude Opus 4.5 Available in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>Claude Opus 4.5 is now available in public preview on
Microsoft Foundry, bringing advanced coding, agentic workflows, and enterprise
productivity to Azure customers. Claude Opus 4.5 sets a new benchmark for performance
and versatility, outperforming previ</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 20:30:10 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-24T20:30:10Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">533437</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=533437</link><category>Launched</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Files</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure File Sync in New Zealand North</title><description>Azure File Sync enables seamless tiering of data from on-premises Windows Servers to Azure Files for hybrid use cases and simplified migration. It also enables you to leverage the performance, flexibility and compatibility of your on-premises File Server </description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:00:42 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-24T18:00:42Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526018</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526018</link><category>In preview</category><category>Identity</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Microsoft Entra ID (formerly Azure AD)</category><category>Azure Bastion</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Entra ID support for RDP connections </title><description>Announcing Azure Bastion now supports Microsoft Entra ID
authentication for RDP connections to Windows VMs directly in the portal. This update
brings two key benefits for RDP users connecting to their virtual machines: Enhanced Security: By eliminating lo</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:15:03 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-24T17:15:03Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">532481</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=532481</link><category>Launched</category><category>Developer tools</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Azure Load Testing</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Load Testing in Italy North</title><description>Azure Load Testing capability in Azure App Testing is now generally available in Italy North. Customers can now use Azure Load Testing, a fully managed load-testing service to generate high scale load and run simulations, easily identify performance bottl</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:00:10 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-24T17:00:10Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">532207</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=532207</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Regex support in T-SQL </title><description>Boost your SQL queries with powerful regular expressions (regex) support for advanced pattern matching. Now you can use native regex in T-SQL directly in Azure SQL and SQL Server 2025 queries—simplifying code, improving maintainability, and reducing depen</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:00:10 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-24T17:00:10Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">532197</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=532197</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Azure Database for MySQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure MCP Server for Azure Database for MySQL </title><description>Announcing that Azure MCP Server now supports Azure Database for MySQL. With this update, you can empower AI agents and applications to interact with your MySQL data using natural language through the open Model Context Protocol (MCP). Instead of writing </description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:00:10 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-24T17:00:10Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">512413</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=512413</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><category>Features</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Custom handler support in Azure Functions Flex consumption </title><description>Azure Functions now supports custom
handlers in Flex consumption. Custom handlers are lightweight web servers that
receive events from the Functions host. Any language that supports HTTP
primitives can implement a custom handler.  Custom handlers are best</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:15:38 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-21T19:15:38Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">501658</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=501658</link><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Machine Learning</category><category>Retirements</category><title>Retirement: Migrate to dedicated VM for your compute clusters</title><description>On September 30, 2025, Low-Priority VM will reach end of life. However, you will continue to be supported on Azure Machine Learning until March 31, 2026.  To ensure that your clusters are not automatically scaled down it is recommended to migrate to dedic</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:45:18 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-21T18:45:18Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523076</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523076</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Container network metrics filtering in Advanced Container Networking Services for (ACNS) for AKS </title><description>Container network metrics
filtering in Azure Container Networking Services (ACNS) is now available in
public preview. In
containerized environments, the ingestion of excessive network metrics can lead
to inflated storage costs and cluttered dashboards, ma</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:00:10 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T20:00:10Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523152</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523152</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: MCP support for AI toolchain operator add-on in AKS</title><description>MCP support for AI toolchain operator add-on is
now Generally Available.    The AI Toolchain Operator add-on now supports
KAITO inference workspaces with integrated tool calling and Model Context
Protocol (MCP), addressing key challenges around dynamic mo</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:45:04 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T18:45:04Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523120</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523120</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Cluster-wide Cilium network policy with Azure CNI powered by Cilium for AKS </title><description>Cluster-wide Cilium network
policy for AKS clusters using Azure CNI powered by Cilium is now Generally
Available.   Managing consistent network policies across Kubernetes
namespaces has long been a challenge for platform teams, especially in
multi-tenant </description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:30:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T18:30:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523081</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523081</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Local redirect policy in Azure CNI powered by Cilium for AKS </title><description>Local redirect policy with Azure
CNI powered by Cilium for AKS is now generally available. Customers running high-scale AKS workloads often experience
latency and performance bottlenecks due to cross-node traffic routing. The new local
redirect policy add</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:30:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T18:30:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523115</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523115</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Layer 7 policy with Advanced Container Networking Services (ACNS) for AKS</title><description>To address the growing need for granular traffic control in
microservices architectures, Azure Container Networking Services now offers
Layer 7 Policy as a generally available feature. This capability empowers
customers to enforce fine-grained traffic con</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:15:25 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T18:15:25Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522077</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522077</link><category>Launched</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure NetApp Files</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure NetApp Files single file restore from backup </title><description>With Azure NetApp Files single file restore from backup, you can restore individual files from Azure NetApp Files backup vault without needing to restore an entire volume. By restoring only the necessary files, you can save time and cost needed for restor</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:15:25 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T18:15:25Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530183</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530183</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure DNS</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: DNS security policy Threat Intelligence feed</title><description>Azure
DNS security policy Threat Intelligence feed is now generally available.
Protect against known malicious domains with Microsoft’s managed Threat
Intelligent feed.  Smart Protection  
 Almost all attacks begin with
     a DNS query. Threat Intelligen</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:00:13 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T17:00:13Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522390</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522390</link><category>Launched</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Sphere</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Sphere OS version 25.10 is now available</title><description>Azure Sphere OS version 25.10 is now available in the Retail feed. This release includes updates to Azure Sphere OS only; it does not include an updated SDK. If your devices are connected to the internet, they will receive the updated OS from the cloud.Th</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:00:12 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T16:00:12Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529797</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529797</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Virtual Machines</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Trusted Launch is now supported for Arm64 Marketplace Images </title><description>Announcing that
Trusted Launch supported Arm64 Images are now available in the Azure
Marketplace. You can now get the dual benefit of cost and performance efficiencies
of Arm64 in addition to the security benefits of Trusted Launch.  Arm64 VMs bring cost
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:00:59 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T15:00:59Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525620</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525620</link><category>In preview</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure NetApp Files</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure NetApp Files migration assistant (portal support) </title><description>Azure NetApp Files migration assistant (with SnapMirror) provides efficient and cost-effective data migration leveraging ONTAP's built-in replication engine for seamless transition from on-premises or CVO/other cloud providers to Azure NetApp Files (ANF).</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:45:47 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T13:45:47Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523917</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523917</link><category>In preview</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure NetApp Files</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure NetApp Files cache volumes    </title><description>Azure NetApp Files cache volumes are now available in public preview. The cache volumes feature is a new capability built on NetApp’s ONTAP FlexCache technology that provides a persistent, high-performance cache in Azure for data stored on ONTAP-based sto</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:45:47 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T13:45:47Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530174</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530174</link><category>In preview</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Arc</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Monitor for Azure Arc-enabled Kubernetes with OpenShift and Azure Red Hat OpenShift</title><description>Azure Monitor provides a complete set of services for monitoring the health and performance of different layers of your Kubernetes infrastructure and the applications that depend on it.Azure Monitor now supports Azure Arc-enabled Kubernetes with OpenShift</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:00:32 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-20T08:00:32Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529381</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529381</link><category>Launched</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Managed Lustre</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Managed Lustre Support for Azure MCP Server</title><description>Azure Managed Lustre now offers full integration with Azure MCP Server, and this capability is generally available. Azure MCP Server enables developers and infrastructure teams to manage Azure resources—including Azure Managed Lustre file systems—using na</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:00:38 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T21:00:38Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529368</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529368</link><category>Launched</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Managed Lustre</category><category>Features</category><category>Management</category><category>Open Source</category><category>Services</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: CSI Dynamic Provisioning for Azure Managed Lustre</title><description>CSI Dynamic Provisioning for Azure Managed Lustre (AMLFS) is now generally available. With dynamic provisioning, Kubernetes applications can request AMLFS-backed persistent volumes on demand using standard StorageClass and PersistentVolumeClaim objects—no</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:00:38 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T21:00:38Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529359</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529359</link><category>In preview</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Managed Lustre</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: 20 MB/s/TiB Performance Tier for Azure Managed Lustre </title><description>Azure Managed Lustre now offers a new 20 MB/s/TiB performance tier in public preview, designed to meet the demands of large-scale AI and high-performance computing (HPC) workloads. This tier enables customers to provision file systems up to 25 PiB in a si</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:00:38 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T21:00:38Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529342</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529342</link><category>In preview</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Managed Lustre</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><category>Services</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Auto-import for Azure Managed Lustre</title><description>The Auto-import feature for Azure Managed Lustre (AMLFS) is now available in public preview. Auto-import enables seamless, policy-driven synchronization of data from Azure Blob Storage containers into AMLFS clusters, automatically reflecting new, changed,</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:00:49 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T20:00:49Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">515505</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=515505</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><category>Features</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Recommended alerts for Azure Monitor Workspace</title><description>Azure Monitor now offers one-click enablement of recommended alerts directly in the Azure Portal for Azure Monitor Managed service for Prometheus customers. These alerts enable you to monitor the ingestion limits for Azure Monitor Workspace and avoid metr</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:45:05 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T17:45:05Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">532188</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=532188</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Managed Redis integration with Microsoft Foundry</title><description>Azure Managed Redis is now available as part of the Microsoft Foundry MCP tools catalog, allowing customers to use Redis as a knowledge store or memory store for AI agents. This integration makes it simple to connect Redis to Foundry-based agents, enablin</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:30:18 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T17:30:18Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">532202</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=532202</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Application Gateway</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: TLS and TCP termination on Azure Application Gateway</title><description>Azure Application Gateway has introduced general availability support
for TLS and TCP protocol termination. This enhancement enables you to load
balance and securely process non-HTTP(S) traffic for applications that rely on
TCP or TLS protocols. The gatew</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:00:30 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T17:00:30Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527678</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527678</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Analytics</category><category>Azure Databricks</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Microsoft Foundry data connection for Azure Databricks</title><description>Azure Databricks Genie is now integrated with Microsoft Foundry and in public preview. You can now connect Genie spaces directly to Microsoft Foundry agents using Model Context Protocol (MCP), giving you seamless access to trusted data for building intell</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:00:30 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T17:00:30Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527668</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527668</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Analytics</category><category>Azure Databricks</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Databricks Genie in Copilot Studio </title><description>Azure Databricks Genie is now available in Microsoft Copilot Studio, giving you direct access to intelligent, enterprise-grade AI answers across your full Azure Databricks data estate. This integration unlocks enterprise-grade, conversational analytics ac</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:00:30 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T17:00:30Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527635</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527635</link><category>In preview</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>API Management</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure API Management adds support for A2A Agent APIs</title><description>Announcing the public preview of A2A API support in Azure API Management.
With this new capability, organizations can manage and govern agent APIs
alongside other API types — AI model APIs, Model Context Protocol (MCP) tools,
and traditional APIs such as </description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:00:30 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T17:00:30Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">532303</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=532303</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Claude in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>Claude models by Anthropic are now
available for Public Preview in Microsoft Foundry, expanding the platform’s unified ecosystem of
frontier AI. Enterprises can access Claude Sonnet 4.5, Opus 4.1, and Haiku 4.5
for advanced long-context reasoning, coding,</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:31 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-19T00:00:31Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526751</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526751</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Copilot</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Copilot agents - a closer look at the deployment agent </title><description>Following our Azure Copilot announcement introducing agentic
capabilities, this update focuses on one of the six new agents: the deployment
agent. The deployment agent helps you discover, plan, and deploy cloud
workloads faster and with confidence using n</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:15:19 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T20:15:19Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529806</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529806</link><category>In development</category><title>[In development] Private Preview: Azure HorizonDB </title><description>Engineered for performance, Azure HorizonDB for PostgreSQL delivers future-proof, autoscaling storage up to 128 TB, up to 3 times faster performance than open-source PostgreSQL, and rapid compute scalability to 3,072 vCores. Now in private preview, Azure </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:00:28 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T18:00:28Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526909</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526909</link><category>Launched</category><category>Developer tools</category><category>Visual Studio Code</category><category>Features</category><category>SDK and Tools</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Private Marketplace for VS Code</title><description>The VS Code Private Marketplace is a secure, enterprise-ready way to host and manage extensions internally—fully integrated with VS Code. Teams can self-host, deploy easily, and manage updates with flexibility and control.Learn more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:00:28 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T18:00:28Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526876</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526876</link><category>In preview</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Security</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Microsoft Defender for Cloud</category><category>GitHub Advanced Security for Azure DevOps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Microsoft Defender for Cloud + GitHub Advanced Security </title><description>With Microsoft Defender for Cloud and GitHub Advanced
Security, protect cloud-native applications across the full app lifecycle from
code to cloud. This natively integrated solution helps unify developers and
security teams in one workflow while staying i</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:00:28 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T18:00:28Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526188</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526188</link><category>In preview</category><category>Storage</category><category>Analytics</category><category>Azure Blob Storage</category><category>Azure Data Lake Storage</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Smart Tier account level tiering (Azure Blob Storage and ADLS)</title><description>Introducing smart tier Public Preview for account level
tiering Announcing the public preview of smart
tier for Azure Blob Storage and Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS). Smart tier
is a fully managed and automated data tiering solution, avoiding manual tier
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:00:28 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T18:00:28Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523623</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523623</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>App Service</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Managed Instance on Azure App Service</title><description>Announcing Managed Instance on Azure App Service, now in Public Preview! This new capability makes it easy to move web apps to the cloud with minimal configuration—no code rewrites required. Whether your .NET apps run on-premises or in VMs, you can move t</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 18:00:28 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T18:00:28Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527713</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527713</link><category>In preview</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Files</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Entra-only identities support with Azure Files SMB </title><description>Azure Files now supports Entra-only identities, enabling customers to retire on-premises domain controllers while maintaining secure SMB access to file shares. This feature delivers a fully cloud-native authentication model using Microsoft Entra Kerberos </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:30:44 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:30:44Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530661</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530661</link><category>In development</category><title>[In development] Private Preview: Azure Boost confidential device</title><description>The
Azure Boost confidential device feature is now in preview. Azure Boost
is a Microsoft Azure system that offloads virtualization tasks—such as
networking, storage, and host management—from the hypervisor and host OS to
purpose-built hardware and softwa</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530609</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530609</link><category>In preview</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Application Gateway</category><category>Azure DDoS Protection</category><category>Web Application Firewall</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Microsoft HTTP DDoS Ruleset 1.0 on Application Gateway WAF v2</title><description>Announcing the public preview
of the HTTP DDoS Ruleset for Application Gateway WAF v2. HTTP-layer DDoS attacks remain a leading cause of
application downtime, and traditional static controls often fall short against
evolving botnets. The new HTTP DDoS Rul</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530287</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530287</link><category>In development</category><title>[In development] Private Preview: Azure Boost remote storage throughput and network bandwidth enhancements</title><description>Remote storage throughput and network bandwidth performance
enhancements for the latest Azure Boost architecture are now in preview. Azure
Boost is a Microsoft Azure system that offloads virtualization tasks—such as
networking, storage, and host managemen</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530208</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530208</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Virtual Machines</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: NCv6 Virtual Machines</title><description>We are announcing the public preview of NCv6 RTX PRO 6000 Blackwell
Server Edition Virtual Machines, as the next enhancement of NC Series VMs
available on Azure.
Nvidia RTX PRO 6000 BSE GPUs are designed to accelerate a wide array of
workloads including v</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529944</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529944</link><category>In preview</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: New integration and extensibility capabilities to Azure SRE Agent</title><description>Azure SRE Agent is an AI-driven solution that unifies operational workflows into a single, prompt-based automation layer—eliminating complexity and reducing overhead for modern cloud operations. Unlike traditional, static automation solutions, SRE Agent l</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529519</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529519</link><category>Launched</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Advanced sampling and richer data collection in Azure Monitor OpenTelemetry Distro</title><description>Azure continues to embrace open standards by adding new capabilities to the Azure Monitor OpenTelemetry Distro that powers Azure Monitor Application Insights. New Capabilities:Rate-limited sampling and
trace-based log sampling:  New sampling options in
th</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527815</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527815</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><category>Network Watcher</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Network Watcher – Agentless Connection Troubleshoot </title><description>Agentless Connection Troubleshoot (public preview)
introduces a faster, simpler, and fully agentless way to diagnose network
connectivity issues across Azure resources. Previously, running connectivity
checks required installing the Network Watcher Extens</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527810</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527810</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><category>Network Watcher</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Network Watcher Topology – AKS Visualization</title><description>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) visualization in
Network Watcher Topology (Public Preview) delivers end-to-end visibility of AKS
clusters directly within the Azure networking experience. Customers can now
explore their Kubernetes environments, including th</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527805</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527805</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Networking</category><category>Network Watcher</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure VNet Flow Log - Filtering </title><description>VNet Flow Log captures IP
traffic flowing through VNets, Subnets, &amp; NICs for monitoring, troubleshooting,
network optimization, security, and compliance needs. This release introduces advanced filtering
capabilities in VNet Flow Logs, empowering users wit</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526729</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526729</link><category>Launched</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure ExpressRoute</category><category>Features</category><category>Services</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: ExpressRoute Scalable Gateway</title><description>ExpressRoute Scalable Gateway (ErGwScale) is our
next-generation offering that brings flexibility, performance, and operational
simplicity to Virtual Network Gateway deployments. With this release, you can
dynamically scale gateway infrastructure to meet </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526644</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526644</link><category>Launched</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Registry</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Container Registry Repository Permissions with Attribute-based Access Control (ABAC)</title><description>Organizations
operating Azure Container Registries (ACR) require least-privilege permissions
over which Microsoft Entra identities can publish or consume container images.
With ACR repository permissions using attribute-based access control (ABAC),
admini</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526242</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526242</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Kubernetes Service desktop </title><description>AKS desktop delivers a modern, application-centric
experience for deploying and managing workloads on Azure Kubernetes Service.
Built on supported AKS features, best practices, and the open-source Headlamp
project, it offers a guided, self-service interfa</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526237</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526237</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Pod sandboxing on AKS </title><description>Running
containerized workloads in shared environments can raise concerns around
security and workload isolation. To address this, AKS now supports pod
sandboxing, enabling customers to run containers in per-workload pod VMs. Each
pod VM is isolated from </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526232</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526232</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Managed namespaces on AKS </title><description>Managing
namespace configurations across AKS clusters has traditionally required manual
setup and ongoing maintenance, creating complexity and potential for
misconfiguration. With the general availability of Managed Namespaces, AKS now
enables users to ea</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526227</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526227</link><category>In preview</category><category>Containers</category><category>Compute</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Fleet Manager</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Kubernetes Fleet Manager for Arc-enabled clusters </title><description>Managing
Kubernetes clusters across hybrid and multi-cloud environments can be complex
and fragmented. To simplify this, Azure Kubernetes Fleet Manager now supports
Azure Arc-enabled Kubernetes, enabling organizations to seamlessly manage any
CNCF-complia</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526213</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526213</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Windows Server 2025 on AKS</title><description>Organizations running Windows-based
workloads on Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) face increasing pressure to
modernize as support timelines for older Windows Server versions approach
retirement. To help customers prepare, AKS now offers preview support for</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526208</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526208</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: AKS Automatic pod readiness SLA</title><description>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) Automatic
clusters now come with a pod readiness SLA, guaranteeing that eligible pods meet
readiness criteria within five minutes at the 99.9th percentile.
This empowers customers to confidently deploy mission critical workl</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526203</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526203</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: AKS Automatic managed system node pools</title><description>Provisioning and maintaining system node pools in AKS
requires ongoing effort to ensure proper scaling, patching, and availability, tasks
that can divert resources from application development and delivery.
Managed system node pools in AKS Automatic remov</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526179</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526179</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Add durability to AI agents in Azure Functions using Microsoft Agent Framework</title><description>You can now build and host reliable
production-grade AI agents using the durable extension for
Microsoft Agent Framework. This integration combines the Microsoft Agent
Framework with Azure Functions’ durable capabilities, delivering proven
orchestration a</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526174</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526174</link><category>In preview</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure Virtual Network Manager</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Cross region pool association support for Azure Virtual Network Manager IP address management</title><description>Managing
IP address spaces across multiple regions can be complex and error-prone.  With
this new capability, you can now associate a single IPAM pool with virtual
networks in multiple regions, simplifying governance and ensuring
consistent CIDR allocatio</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526169</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526169</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure Virtual Network Manager</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Virtual Network Manager address overlap prevention in mesh </title><description>Azure Virtual Network Manager
address space overlap prevention in mesh is now generally available, bringing enhanced
reliability and governance to multi-virtual network environments. Unintended
address overlap within mesh can lead to dropped traffic. This</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526077</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526077</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Functions support for Node.js 24 </title><description>You can now develop functions using Node.js 24 locally and deploy them
to Azure Functions on Windows and Linux.   Note: Node.js 24 does not support
32-bit systems on Windows. To ensure compatibility, new Windows Function Apps for
Node.js 24 now default to</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526072</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526072</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Functions support for Java 25 </title><description>You can now develop functions using Java
25 locally and deploy them to Azure Functions on Windows and Linux.  Upgrade your apps to Java 25 to take
advantage of enhanced security, a longer support window, and continued
compatibility with the Azure Function</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525893</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525893</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Application Gateway</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Application Gateway for Containers – Slow start</title><description>Slow start is now
generally available as a load balancing algorithm in Application Gateway for
Containers. This feature improves stability and performance during backend
scale-up by gradually increasing traffic to new pods over a configurable time
window.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525874</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525874</link><category>In preview</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Application Gateway</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Application Gateway for Containers Istio Service Mesh integration</title><description>Application
Gateway for Containers now supports integration with Istio service mesh through
an optional service mesh extension. This feature simplifies secure north-south
communication between external clients and services within the service mesh. Single </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525549</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525549</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure DocumentDB high-performance storage </title><description>Now you can run bigger, faster workloads on fewer nodes using high-performance storage for Azure DocumentDB. This update delivers up to 64 TiB capacity, 80,000 IOPS, and 1,200 MB/s throughput per physical shard (node). Storage IOPS and throughput on Azure</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525523</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525523</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Model Context Protocol (MCP) tool trigger for Azure Functions </title><description>Model
Context Protocol (MCP) is a way for apps to provide capabilities and context to
a large language model. A key feature of MCP is the ability to define tools
that AI agents can leverage to accomplish whatever tasks they’ve been given.
MCP servers can </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525518</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525518</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Functions durable task scheduler Dedicated SKU (GA) &amp; Consumption SKU (Public Preview)</title><description>Earlier this year, we
introduced Azure Functions durable task scheduler, an orchestration engine
designed for complex workflows and intelligent agents. It automatically
checkpoints progress and protects your orchestration state, enabling resilient
and rel</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525505</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525505</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Self-hosted remote MCP servers on Azure Functions </title><description>We are introducing a new capability that allows you to host
remote Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers built with the MCP SDKs on Functions. Some key benefits of hosting on the Functions platform include:  Built-in server authentication Automatic and bur</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525500</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525500</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[Launched] Announcing: Resources for migrating to Azure Functions Flex Consumption </title><description>Azure Functions Flex Consumption is
now the recommended hosting plan for serverless workloads requiring advanced
scaling, networking, and cost optimization. To support customers migrating from
the Azure Functions Consumption plan or from AWS Lambda, Micro</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525479</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525479</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Functions</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Functions enables OpenTelemetry support </title><description>Azure Functions now supports
OpenTelemetry in general availability (GA), enabling developers to export logs,
traces, and metrics using open standards. This release builds on the public
preview and delivers a production-ready observability experience for s</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525470</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525470</link><category>In preview</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Container Apps adds support for agentic Docker Compose </title><description>Azure Container Apps is bringing the familiar
developer workflow of Docker Compose directly to Azure Container Apps. As one
of the most widely adopted tools among developers, Docker Compose simplifies
defining and running multi-container applications, and</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525465</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525465</link><category>In preview</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Container Apps introduces flexible workload profile </title><description>Flexible workload profile represents a new option
that blends the simplicity of consumption with many of the performance and
control characteristics of dedicated workload profiles. This offers the same
easy-to-understand, pay-per-use serverless model as C</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525460</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525460</link><category>Launched</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Container Apps serverless GPUs in additional regions </title><description>To
meet growing demand for GPU-powered workloads, Azure Container Apps serverless GPUs are now generally
available in additional regions. This expansion enables developers to run AI
inference, model training, and GPU-accelerated workloads with the simplic</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525455</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525455</link><category>In preview</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Confidential computing in Azure Container Apps</title><description>Confidential
computing support in Azure Container Apps is now in public preview. This
release brings hardware-based Trusted Execution Environments (TEEs) to your
containerized workloads. Azure already provides encryption of data at rest and
in transit, an</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525405</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525405</link><category>In preview</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure NAT Gateway</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Standard V2 NAT Gateway and StandardV2 Public IPs</title><description>StandardV2 SKU NAT Gateway is now in public preview, delivering next-generation capabilities for scalable and resilient outbound connectivity. New offerings: Zone-Redundancy: Built for high availability in availability zone supported regions. Traffic surv</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525388</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525388</link><category>Launched</category><category>Analytics</category><category>Microsoft Fabric</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: SQL database in Microsoft Fabric</title><description>SQL database in Fabric is now generally available. Built on the trusted SQL Server and Azure SQL Database engine, this fully SaaS-native solution empowers developers and data professionals to unify operational and analytical workloads with speed, security</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523824</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523824</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Support for Italian and Portuguese in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL full-text search </title><description>Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL now supports Italian and Portuguese languages in full-text search, available today in public preview. This update adds to the list of supported languages, enabling you to build rich, language-aware search experiences that underst</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523814</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523814</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Cosmos DB MCP ToolKit for Microsoft Foundry Agent Service </title><description>Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL now offers an MCP Toolkit that can be used with Microsoft Foundry  Agent Service, available today in public preview.  This new integration allows you to connect Microsoft Foundry Agents directly to data in Azure Cosmos DB. By dep</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523809</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523809</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Fuzzy search in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL full-text search </title><description>Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL now supports fuzzy search in full-text search. With fuzzy search, you can deliver typo-tolerant, error-resilient search experiences directly within Azure Cosmos DB, helping your users find the right results even when queries or t</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523803</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523803</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Vector indexing performance improvements in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL </title><description>This release gives you faster vector inserts and index builds in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL, helping you reduce end-to-end ingestion and indexing times for large AI workloads. This improvement is powered by algorithmic enhancements to our vector indexing e</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523796</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523796</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Float16 data type for vector indexes in Azure Cosmos DB </title><description>Azure Cosmos DB now supports float 16 data types for vector indexes. With this update, you can store and query vectors using half-precision floating-point numbers. Using float16 cuts storage usage in half compared to float32, while maintaining high retrie</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523782</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523782</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB for Visual Studio Code  </title><description>Developers today are building more intelligent, connected, and autonomous applications than ever before. From personalized chatbots and copilots to dynamic content engines and decision systems, data is the foundation of these agentic experiences.  Azure C</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523773</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523773</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB Mirroring in Microsoft Fabric </title><description>Now generally available, Azure Cosmos DB Mirroring in Fabric enables you to seamlessly integrate your existing operational workloads with the analytical capabilities of Microsoft Fabric. You can take advantage of the innovations in Fabric, running SQL que</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523768</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523768</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Analytics</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><category>Microsoft Fabric</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Cosmos DB in Microsoft Fabric </title><description>Now generally available, Cosmos DB in Fabric enables you to build operational and analytical workloads in Microsoft Fabric. You can use the AI-features in Azure Cosmos DB plus the innovations in Fabric to run SQL queries over JSON data and build real-time</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523763</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523763</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Index Advisor for Azure DocumentDB </title><description>Integrated into the DocumentDB for VS Code extension, the Index Advisor enables you to view and debug database performance. It uses natural language to recommend optimal indexing and best practices for your MongoDB workloads.  Learn more. </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523754</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523754</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Priority-based execution in Azure Cosmos DB </title><description>You can now enable priority-based execution in Azure Cosmos DB to ensure that high-priority requests are favored during periods of contention. The system will throttle low-priority requests first, allowing high-priority operations to proceed on a best-eff</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523745</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523745</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Cosmos DB Fleet Analytics </title><description>You can now unify insights across your entire Azure Cosmos DB footprint using Azure Cosmos DB Fleet Analytics, available in public preview. Fleet Analytics helps you manage data across multiple accounts, subscriptions, and workloads, providing large-scale</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523740</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523740</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB fleet pools  </title><description>Now you can more easily operate your Azure Cosmos DB accounts at scale. Azure Cosmos DB fleet pools give you new capabilities when building multitenant software as a service (SaaS) applications.  You can simplify capacity management by creating a pool of </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523735</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523735</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure DocumentDB - an open-source, MongoDB-compatible document database service for hybrid and multicloud</title><description>Microsoft is announcing the general availability of Azure DocumentDB, a fully managed document database service built on the open-source, MongoDB-compatible DocumentDB, now governed by the Linux Foundation. Formerly known as Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB (v</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523726</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523726</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Dynamic data masking with Azure Cosmos DB </title><description>You can now help protect sensitive data from unauthorized access using dynamic data masking (DDM), a server-side, policy-based security feature in Azure Cosmos DB. DDM dynamically masks data for non-privileged users, ensuring that sensitive information is</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523721</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523721</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Online and offline migrations in Azure DocumentDB Migration extension </title><description>You can now migrate MongoDB workloads to Azure DocumentDB using the new Azure DocumentDB Migration extension for Visual Studio Code—now available in public preview. This seamless, zero-cost migration supports both online and offline modes, simplifying and</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523716</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523716</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Online migration from Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB RU to Azure DocumentDB</title><description>Announcing the general availability of seamless, self-serve online migrations from Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB RU to Azure DocumentDB—directly from the Azure portal. With this release, your organization can modernize its MongoDB workloads with zero downti</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523593</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523593</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Oracle to PostgreSQL migration tooling in Visual Studio Code </title><description>Migrating from Oracle to PostgreSQL is now simpler and faster with the new Oracle-to-PostgreSQL migration tooling, available directly in the Azure Database for PostgreSQL extension for Visual Studio Code.  This new tool helps you seamlessly convert your O</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523588</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523588</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: 2025 REST API for Azure Database for PostgreSQL </title><description>Announcing the general availability of the 2025 REST API for Azure Database for PostgreSQL. This release adds support for PostgreSQL 17 and 18, so you can adopt new versions without changing your automation patterns. You can also now set the default datab</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523583</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523583</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Elastic clusters on Azure Database for PostgreSQL – Flexible Server </title><description>Now you can use elastic clusters to horizontally scale Azure Database for PostgreSQL through row-based and schema-based sharding. Elastic clusters make it easy to build multitenant apps by offloading shard management and operations—such as tenant isolatio</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523578</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523578</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Native Microsoft Foundry support for Azure Database for PostgreSQL</title><description>Announcing the public preview of Microsoft Foundry support for Azure Database for PostgreSQL. The Azure PostgreSQL MCP Server is now natively integrated with Microsoft Foundry.  This integration enables you to build AI agents to securely query and analyze</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523569</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523569</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Database for PostgreSQL – Flexible Server anon extension </title><description>The anon extension is now generally available in Azure Database for PostgreSQL flexible server. This extension provides data anonymization tools. Learn more. </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523564</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523564</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Public Preview: Azure Database for PostgreSQL – Flexible Server v6 series VMs and AMD v6 Confidential Compute</title><description>Now you can deploy general purpose and memory-optimized v6-series Azure Virtual Machines with local NVMe storage in Azure Database for PostgreSQL flexible server. The v6 series is available with either Intel or AMD processor options. Learn more.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523559</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523559</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Database for PostgreSQL – Flexible Server pg_duckdb extension </title><description>Now you can create pg_duckdb extensions in Azure Database for PostgreSQL flexible server, so you can accelerate analytics using DuckDB’s vectorized, columnar execution.  Learn more. </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523533</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523533</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure SQL change event streaming </title><description>You can now stream data changes in near real time from Azure SQL Database directly into Azure Event Hubs. With the public preview of change event streaming (CES), you can streamline data integration and support enhanced analytics, event-driven architectur</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523196</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523196</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: PostgreSQL 18 with in-place upgrade on Azure Database for PostgreSQL </title><description>You can now use PostgreSQL 18 on Azure Database for PostgreSQL. This release introduces the latest PostgreSQL innovations along with seamless in-place upgrade support, allowing you to move from earlier versions without changing your server endpoint, recon</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523187</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523187</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: PostgreSQL extension for Visual Studio Code with GitHub Copilot  </title><description>Announcing that the PostgreSQL extension for Visual Studio Code is generally available. With this powerful tool, you can connect to PostgreSQL database instances, run queries, create and manage connection profiles, and take advantage of Microsoft Entra ID</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523177</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523177</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Mirroring in Fabric for PostgreSQL Flexible Server  </title><description>You can now bring data together and simplify analytics using Microsoft Fabric mirroring for Azure Database for PostgreSQL flexible server, now generally available. Mirroring in Fabric unifies your organizational data in OneLake and supports network-isolat</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523167</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523167</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Database for PostgreSQL</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Database for PostgreSQL storage extension support for Parquet </title><description>Announcing that Azure Database for PostgreSQL flexible server now supports the Azure Storage extension with Parquet format and multiple compression options. You can seamlessly read and write Parquet files directly from your database, enabling faster data </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523125</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523125</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Azure SQL Managed Instance</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure SQL Managed Instance Next-gen General Purpose service tier </title><description>The Next‑gen General Purpose tier delivers a major performance boost while preserving the cost advantages you expect. You get more power and compute flexibility without sacrificing the simplicity of a fully managed platform as a service (PaaS) experience.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523110</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523110</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><category>Azure SQL Managed Instance</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure SQL Database DiskANN vector indexing </title><description>Announcing the public preview of vector indexing using DiskANN in Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance and SQL database in Microsoft Fabric. DiskANN is an algorithm for efficient vector similarity search, making it ideal for product recommendati</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523105</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523105</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><title>[In preview] Generally Available: MSSQL extension integration with GitHub Copilot in Visual Studio Code  </title><description>The MSSQL extension for Visual Studio Code now integrates GitHub Copilot, bringing AI-powered SQL assistance directly into your development workflow. Together, they help you reduce repetitive tasks, accelerate development, and design database schemas and </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523095</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523095</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure SQL Database long-term retention (LTR) backup immutability </title><description>You can now configure immutability for Azure SQL Database LTR backups to meet compliance and regulatory needs. Once immutability is configured, the backups can’t be edited or deleted until the specified retention expires, mitigating any potential ransomwa</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522586</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522586</link><category>Launched</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) 22 </title><description>SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS) has long been the trusted tool for managing SQL databases, writing T-SQL, and troubleshooting issues. With SSMS 22, built on Visual Studio 2026, you get support for SQL Server 2025, improved integration with SQL databas</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522581</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522581</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Microsoft Python driver for SQL Server </title><description>Announcing that the mssql-python driver is now generally available. This milestone marks a major step forward in delivering a modern, high-performance, and developer-friendly experience for Python developers working with SQL Server, Azure SQL Database, an</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522572</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522572</link><category>Launched</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure Arc</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: New SQL Server migration in Azure Arc </title><description>A new SQL Server migration in Azure Arc solution streamlines and accelerates your journey to Azure SQL Managed Instance. Powered by Azure Database Migration Service and assisted by Copilot, it delivers an automated, end-to-end migration process that inclu</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522559</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522559</link><category>Launched</category><title>[Launched] Generally Availabe: SQL Server 2025 </title><description>SQL Server 2025, the AI-ready enterprise database, is now generally available, marking a major milestone in Microsoft’s mission to modernize enterprise data platforms. This release introduces built-in AI capabilities, seamless integration with Microsoft F</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522523</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522523</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><category>Azure SQL Managed Instance</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure SQL updates for November 2025 </title><description>In November 2025, the following updates and enhancements were made to Azure SQL:  Apply the reservation discount for a 1-year or 3-year reservation of a zone-redundant Azure SQL Managed Instance in the General Purpose tier to both the standard compute and</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522514</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522514</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Hybrid + multicloud</category><category>Azure SQL Database</category><category>Azure SQL Managed Instance</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure SQL updates for November 2025 </title><description>In November 2025, the following updates and enhancements were made to Azure SQL: View, modify, insert rows in a table without manually writing T-SQL code using the interactive Edit Data interface in the MSSQL extension for Visual Studio Code. Learn more. </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">512949</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=512949</link><category>In preview</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Dynamic sessions shell environment and MCP support in Azure Container Apps</title><description>Azure Container Apps now supports dynamic shell sessions in public
preview. A shell session is a platform-managed built-in container used to
run and execute common shell commands in an isolated sandboxed
environment.  With Azure Container Apps dynamic ses</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">512900</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=512900</link><category>In preview</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Deployment labels in Azure Container Apps</title><description>Azure
Container Apps now supports deployment labels in public preview as a new
deployment mode. This feature simplifies environment management and enables
advanced deployment strategies for your applications by allowing you to assign
meaningful names—such</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">512850</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=512850</link><category>Launched</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Rule-based routing in Azure Container Apps</title><description>Azure Container Apps support for rule-based routing is now
generally available. This feature provides greater flexibility and
composability to your Azure Container Apps by simplifying your architecture for
microservice applications, A/B testing, blue-gree</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">512813</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=512813</link><category>Launched</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Container Apps</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Premium Ingress in Azure Container Apps</title><description>Azure
Container Apps support for premium ingress is now generally available. This
feature introduces environment-level ingress configuration options, with the
primary highlight being customizable ingress scaling. This capability supports
the scaling of th</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">489855</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=489855</link><category>In preview</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Application Gateway</category><category>Features</category><category>Security</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: JWT Validation in Azure Application Gateway</title><description>Announcing the preview of JSON Web Token (JWT) validation in Azure Application Gateway — enabling authentication and token validation right at the Application gateway before traffic reaches your backend applications or APIs.Why It mattersProtect at the pe</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">488990</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=488990</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Application Gateway</category><category>Features</category><category>Services</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Application Gateway mTLS passthrough support</title><description>Announcing a new mTLS enhancement in Azure Application Gateway for backend applications that perform client certificate and authorization header validation at the backend while still requiring web traffic inspection through the Web Application Firewall (W</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:01:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T17:01:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">528538</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=528538</link><category>In preview</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Copilot observability agent</title><description>Cloud operations need more than reactive troubleshooting, they demand intelligent observability that scales across resources and delivers actionable insights when services aren’t performing as expected.Introducing the Azure Copilot observability agent tha</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:30:36 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:30:36Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">531783</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=531783</link><category>In development</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[In development] Private Preview: ActiveMQ and JMS connector for Azure Logic Apps</title><description>Announcing private preview of Active MQ/JMS connector in Azure Logic Apps. With this capability, you can now connect to enterprise messaging systems built on ActiveMQ and JMS for advanced hybrid integration scenarios. </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">531778</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=531778</link><category>In preview</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: New healthcare connectors for Azure Logic Apps</title><description>Announcing new capabilities in Azure Logic Apps that expand healthcare interoperability support through a rich set of connectors. The following connectors are now in public preview: HL7 connector: Enable seamless healthcare data exchange using HL7 messagi</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530797</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530797</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Virtual Machines</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Scheduled Actions </title><description>Schedule Actions gives the ability to manage the lifecycle of VMs at high scale on a periodic basis. Subscription throttling and retries due to transient errors are handled automatically to ensure that your operations succeed without additional overhead.W</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530614</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530614</link><category>Launched</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Microsoft Marketplace</title><description>Microsoft Marketplace — your trusted source for cloud solutions, AI apps, and agents — is now globally available following its launch in the United States in September. All traffic from legacy storefronts (Azure Marketplace and AppSource) is now redirecte</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530593</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530593</link><category>Launched</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><category>Features</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Resale enabled offers through Microsoft Marketplace  </title><description>To help commercial customers maximize their technology innovation with Azure, Microsoft Marketplace is fully embracing the channel-led Marketplace opportunity with the general availability of resale enabled offers.  Resale enabled offers enable software c</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530257</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530257</link><category>In preview</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: GitHub Copilot app modernization expanded capabilities</title><description>Announcing new enhancements to GitHub Copilot App
Modernization that are in Public Preview, making it easier than ever to modernize applications,
databases, containers, and accelerate migration to Azure. Below are the new
capabilities in public preview.  </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529416</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529416</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Virtual Machines</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Industry-leading storage performance Ebsv6 VM series</title><description>Announcing the public preview of the new Azure Ebsv6 VM series, powered by 5th Generation Intel® Xeon® processors. The Ebsv6 and Ebdsv6 VMs deliver up to and industry leading 800,000 IOPS and 14 GBps of remote disk storage throughput, providing high-perfo</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">528899</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=528899</link><category>In development</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure NetApp Files</category><title>[In development] Public Preview: User and group quota reports in Azure NetApp Files </title><description>For organizations leveraging individual user and group quotas in Azure NetApp Files to manage capacity on NFS, SMB, and dual-protocol volumes, the user and group quota reporting feature offers clear visibility into key metrics such as quota limits, used c</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527683</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527683</link><category>Launched</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: New Hybrid Integration Connectors for Azure Logic Apps</title><description>Announcing new capabilities in Azure Logic
Apps that expand hybrid integration through a rich set of connectors. The following connectors are now generally available: Confluent Kafka connector: Connect Logic Apps to
Confluent Cloud for event streaming and</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527673</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527673</link><category>In preview</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Redesigned designer experience for Azure Logic Apps [Standard]</title><description>Announcing the public preview of the
redesigned designer experience for Azure Logic Apps (Standard), a major update
that makes building, editing, and managing workflows faster and more intuitive. The new designer brings run history and workflow editing
cl</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527663</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527663</link><category>In preview</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: New Agent Loop capabilities in Azure Logic Apps</title><description>Announcing a new set of capabilities for
Agent Loop in Azure Logic Apps, now in public preview. These updates expand how
organizations can build, secure, and deploy agentic workflows across their
enterprise environments enabling more flexible AI orchestra</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527658</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527658</link><category>In preview</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Agent Loop in Azure Logic Apps [Consumption]</title><description>Announcing the public preview of Agent Loop
in Azure Logic Apps (Consumption) — bringing agentic intelligence and adaptive
workflows to the serverless Logic Apps runtime. Agent Loop enables you to move beyond traditional, static
automation by creating goa</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527649</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527649</link><category>Launched</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Agent Loop in Azure Logic Apps [Standard]</title><description>Announcing the general availability of Agent
Loop in Azure Logic Apps (Standard), a breakthrough capability that redefines
how organizations design and automate business processes. Agent Loop enables you to move beyond traditional workflow
automation by b</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527644</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527644</link><category>Launched</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Logic Apps</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Automated Testing Framework for Logic Apps [Standard]</title><description>We’re pleased to
announce the general availability of automated testing for Azure Logic Apps
(Standard) in the Visual Studio Code extension. This new capability empowers
developers and integration specialists to build more reliable workflows by
simplifyin</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527626</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527626</link><category>Launched</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>API Management</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Govern Model Context Protocol (MCP) endpoints using Azure API Management</title><description>Model Context Protocol (MCP) governance in
Azure API Management (APIM) is now generally available.This release extends Azure API Management’s proven
governance, security, and observability model to a new generation of AI-driven
workloads. Enterprises can </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527621</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527621</link><category>Launched</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>API Management</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><category>Pricing &amp; Offerings</category><title>[Launched] Announcing: API Center Standard now included at no additional cost for linked Azure API Management Standard and Premium tiers</title><description>API Center Standard,
previously a separate paid offering, is now included at no additional cost for
all Azure API Management Standard and Premium customers, when an API Center
instance is linked with a corresponding Azure API Management service (for both
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527612</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527612</link><category>Launched</category><category>Integration</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>API Management</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Premium v2 tier in Azure API Management</title><description>Announcing the general availability of the Azure API Management Premium v2 tier,
our most powerful and scalable option for managing APIs at enterprise scale. Premium v2
delivers superior performance, the highest entity limits, unlimited included
API calls</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527236</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527236</link><category>Launched</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Red Hat OpenShift</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: OpenShift Virtualization now available on Azure Red Hat OpenShift</title><description>Red Hat OpenShift Virtualization is now generally available on Azure Red Hat OpenShift (ARO), enabling customers to manage virtual machines and containers from one cloud-native platform. This GA builds on feedback from the preview announced at Red Hat Sum</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526742</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526742</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Microsoft Foundry Fine-Tuning Updates</title><description>Microsoft
Foundry Fine-Tuning is updated to reflect a complete redesign of Foundry’s UI,
delivering an agent-first experience for developers and data scientists. The
new interface streamlines model creation, evaluation, and deployment,
integrates with VS </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526665</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526665</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Microsoft Foundry Control Plane &amp; Entra Agent ID</title><description>Microsoft Foundry introduces a unified platform
for enterprise AI agent observability, security, and governance. The Control
Plane integrates identity, monitoring, and compliance, providing centralized
control, deep observability, and compliance for agent</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526618</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526618</link><category>Launched</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: GitHub Copilot app modernization expanded capabilities</title><description>Announcing new enhancements to GitHub Copilot App
Modernization that are Generally Available, making it easier than ever to modernize applications, databases,
containers, and accelerate migration to Azure. Below capabilities are
now Generally Available: F</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526330</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526330</link><category>Launched</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Model Router in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>Model router in Microsoft Foundry is now generally
available. Model router is an AI orchestration layer dynamically selects the
optimal model for each prompt. It now supports a broader range of models
including: GPT-4 family, GPT-5 family, GPT-oss, Deepse</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526198</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526198</link><category>In development</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In development] Private Preview: Foundry Local Android support</title><description>Foundry Local now extends its capabilities to
Android, in addition to Windows and Mac supporting
advanced on-device AI for smartphones, tablets, and IoT devices, while Whisper model integration delivers
robust, privacy-preserving speech and audio processi</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526193</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526193</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Foundry Local updates</title><description>Foundry Local now extends its capabilities, supporting the Whisper model and advanced on-device AI for
smartphones, tablets, and IoT devices. Whisper model integration delivers robust, privacy-preserving
speech and audio processing. The redesigned Foundry</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526150</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526150</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Foundry IQ by Azure AI Search</title><description>Foundry
IQ, powered by Azure AI Search, is a knowledge system that delivers a smarter way to ground agents in enterprise
data. Agents only need to connect to a single knowledge base to access
multiple sources, removing the need to manage separate APIs and</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526132</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526132</link><category>Launched</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Foundry Tools (rebrand from Azure AI Services)</title><description>Foundry Tools (rebranded from Azure AI Services)
provide a unified suite of prebuilt, production-ready AI capabilities for
audio, video, images, documents, and text. Seamlessly integrated into the Microsoft
Foundry platform, these tools empower developers</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526123</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526123</link><category>Launched</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Content Understanding in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>With the general availability of Content Understanding, the service now enables connecting to Foundry models, allowing customers to use Foundry model deployments. Additional key updates include support for VNETs, Managed Identities, Customer Managed Keys </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526114</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526114</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Enrich agents with a unified catalog of prebuilt and custom tools in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>With these latest updates in public preview, Microsoft Foundry enables developers to enrich agents with real-time business context, multimodal capabilities, and custom business logic through a unified catalog of Model Context Protocol (MCP) tools.​Unified</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526004</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526004</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Built-in memory in Foundry Agent Service</title><description>The new long-term memory in Foundry Agent Service gives developers a robust, scalable foundation for agents that can remember, adapt, and act coherently across sessions and workflows. Integrated directly into the Foundry runtime, memory provides a persist</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525999</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525999</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Multi-agent workflows in Foundry Agent Service</title><description>Developers can now
build robust multi-agent workflows using both a visual designer and code-first
API. These workflows provide structured orchestration, context sharing,
persistent state, and error recovery for complex enterprise processes. The
modular de</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525994</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525994</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Hosted agents in Foundry Agent Service</title><description>Hosted agents in Foundry Agent Service make it effortless for teams to move
from local experimentation to full-scale production.Developers can now deploy custom-code agents
built with Microsoft Agent Framework, LangGraph, CrewAI,
or other open-source fram</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525985</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525985</link><category>Launched</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Observability in Foundry Control Plane</title><description>Observability in Foundry Control Plane now in public preview for agents with a GA pre-announcement for model evals is a comprehensive suite of capabilities that enable developers to evaluate, monitor, and optimize the quality, performance, and safety of m</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525976</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525976</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Enterprise MCP enhancements in Foundry Agent Service</title><description>Microsoft Foundry has enhanced integration to Enterprise MCP to enable secure, authenticated connections to MCP servers, allowing credentials to be passed to MCP servers securely. These updates enable enhanced flexibility, security, and compliance when in</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525971</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525971</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Microsoft Foundry one-click deploy channels in Teams, M365 and non-Microsoft</title><description>Microsoft Foundry now
enables one-click, no-code publishing of custom agents to Microsoft Teams and
Microsoft 365 Copilot. This feature removes the complexity of pro-code
deployment, allowing organizations to instantly reach millions of users while
mainta</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525962</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525962</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: LLM Speech in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>LLM Speech in
Microsoft Foundry brings advanced large language model capabilities to speech,
delivering transcription and translation with unmatched fluency and contextual
awareness. With enhanced
multilingual support and advanced prompt tuning, this API </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525957</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525957</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Bring Your Own AI Gateway to Foundry Agent Service</title><description>The BYO AI Model Gateway feature allows enterprises to connect Foundry-hosted
models through any AI gateway services like Azure API Management, Mulesoft, and
Kong, to Foundry Agent Service. The Agent Service honors pre/post‑LLM hooks,
policy‑based model s</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525952</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525952</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Announcing: Developer Training tier for low-cost fine-tuning training</title><description>Microsoft Foundry now has a Developer Training
tier, offering ultra-low-cost model training by leveraging spot capacity. It’s designed to match the affordability of
Developer tier for hosting but applied to the training phase of
fine-tuning workflows.​ Th</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525942</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525942</link><category>Launched</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Streamline IT governance, security, and cost management experiences with Microsoft Foundry</title><description>Microsoft Foundry streamlines AI development and management
for the enterprise. These features are now generally available, empowering IT
admins to deploy AI solutions while meeting enterprise-grade security,
compliance, and governance requirement: Manage</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525933</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525933</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: New granular controls for network and integration security in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>Microsoft Foundry streamlines AI development and management for the enterprise. We're introducing more granular controls for network and integration security and resource management that empower IT admins to deploy AI solutions while meeting enterprise-gr</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525923</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525923</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><category>Security</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Agent mitigations and guardrail customization </title><description>Introducing guardrails for agents in Microsoft Foundry Control Plane. Formerly called content filters, guardrails can now be applied at the agent level rather than only to model deployments. They include existing controls to help mitigate prompt injection</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525536</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525536</link><category>In preview</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: OpenTelemetry visualizations and enhanced monitoring experience in Azure Monitor for Azure VMs and Arc Servers</title><description>OpenTelemetry based visualizations in Azure Monitor are in public preview, along with an enhanced, unified monitoring experience for Azure Virtual Machines and Arc Servers. This release consolidates key monitoring capabilities into a single view and intro</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">525150</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=525150</link><category>In development</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure NetApp Files</category><title>[In development] Public Preview: Large volumes up to 7.2 PiB     </title><description>The Large Volumes up to 7.2 PiB with Cool Access feature allows you to create Azure NetApp Files volumes up to 7.2 PiB on dedicated capacity, designed for workloads where most data are rarely accessed. This enhancement extends cool-access support beyond t</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523614</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523614</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Policy</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Built-in CIS benchmarks for Azure endorsed Linux distros in Machine Config</title><description>Microsoft
Azure now offers built-in Center for Internet Security (CIS) benchmarks in
public preview for all Azure endorsed Linux distributions through Azure Machine
Configuration’s new customizable security benchmarks capability, powered by azure-osconfig</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">522554</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=522554</link><category>In preview</category><category>AI + machine learning</category><category>Microsoft Foundry</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: New AI templates in Microsoft Foundry</title><description>Microsoft Foundry introduces new ready-to-use, customizable AI templates for popular use cases such as live voice agents, release management, data unification, and SharePoint integration applications. These templates eliminate repetitive setup tasks, redu</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">521941</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=521941</link><category>Launched</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Monitor unified onboarding experience for AKS and VMs</title><description>Azure Monitor now offers a unified, single-click onboarding experience for both Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) clusters and virtual machines (VMs). This new experience simplifies setup by automatically deploying the latest Azure Monitor capabilities with </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">520762</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=520762</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Copilot</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><category>Features</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Copilot brings new intelligent agents to support end-to-end lifecycle management of workloads</title><description>Azure Copilot introduces specialized
agents (gated preview) to help migrate,
operate, and modernize workloads anywhere. Copilot evolves chat into an
immersive, full-screen command center (public preview) powered by GPT-5
reasoning, artifact generation, an</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">503704</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=503704</link><category>In preview</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><category>Features</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Dynamic threshold for Log search alerts</title><description>We’re bringing Azure Monitor’s dynamic threshold capabilities to Log search alerts!Using dynamic thresholds means you don't have to know the right threshold for each Log alert rule - Dynamic thresholds calculate the most appropriate thresholds for you.Key</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">492303</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=492303</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>App Service</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Custom error pages on Azure App Service</title><description>Custom error pages are now generally available on App Service. When using custom error pages you can configure your apps to present an error page of your choosing instead of the default error pages that are presented to your users. Learn more. </description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">467471</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=467471</link><category>In preview</category><category>Databases</category><category>Internet of Things</category><category>Azure Cosmos DB</category><category>Features</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Online container copy in Azure Cosmos DB </title><description>You can now minimize downtime when you copy data across containers in Azure Cosmos DB accounts. You can use online container copy in Azure Cosmos DB to copy data from one container to another in real time. Your application using the source container remai</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:00:16 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T16:00:16Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">527181</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=527181</link><category>Launched</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Blob Storage</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: The Archive access tier for Azure Blob Storage is now generally available in the Taiwan North region</title><description>The Archive access tier for Azure Blob Storage is now generally available in the Taiwan North region.With this regional expansion, customers in Taiwan can now store infrequently accessed data in the cost-effective Archive tier, while meeting data residenc</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:03 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T14:00:03Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">516656</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=516656</link><category>In preview</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure NetApp Files</category><category>Features</category><title>[In preview] Public preview: Support for large volume breakthrough mode</title><description>Breakthrough mode in Azure NetApp Files enables extreme performance and scalability for demanding HPC and EDA workloads. It supports large volumes up to 2PiB, delivering throughput up to 50GiBps, depending on workload characteristics. Breakthrough mode us</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:03 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T14:00:03Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">520454</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=520454</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Storage</category><category>Azure Backup</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Threat Detection in Azure Backup powered by MDC</title><description>Azure Backup has introduced threat detection capabilities for Azure VM backups, powered by Microsoft Defender for Cloud (MDC). This new capability enables customers to assess the health of their Azure VM backup restore points (RPs) by identifying maliciou</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:45:04 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T13:45:04Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">518469</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=518469</link><category>In preview</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><category>Microsoft Ignite</category><category>Features</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Query-based metric alerts in Azure Monitor</title><description>Azure Monitor metric
alerts now support all Azure metrics - including platform,
Prometheus, and custom metrics - giving you complete coverage for your monitoring
needs. In addition, metric alerts now offer powerful query capabilities with PromQL, the indu</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:00:28 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-18T08:00:28Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">529528</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=529528</link><category>In preview</category><category>DevOps</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Azure Monitor</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Introducing SDK Stats to the Azure Monitor OpenTelemetry Distro</title><description>As part of our journey to make Azure the most observable cloud, we are adding a new way for you to observe your Azure Monitor Application Insights data collection pipeline. One of the foremost reasons customers file support tickets against Azure Monitor A</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:00:46 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-17T20:00:46Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526900</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526900</link><category>Launched</category><category>Developer tools</category><category>Visual Studio</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Visual Studio 2026</title><description>Visual Studio 2026 is the next evolution of the world’s most trusted IDE—modernized with AI deeply integrated into everyday workflows. By seamlessly integrating GitHub Copilot and agentic workflows, Visual Studio empowers professional developers to move f</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:45:44 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-17T18:45:44Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530092</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530092</link><category>Launched</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Migration</category><category>Azure Site Recovery</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Seamless failback for HyperV-to-Azure: Managed Disk support in Azure Site Recovery </title><description>Azure Site Recovery now enables failback from Azure VMs to on-premises Hyper-V, even if replication from on-premises to Azure happened to storage account and the failed-over Azure VM uses managed disks. Learn more. </description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:12 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-17T16:30:12Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530087</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530087</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Migration</category><category>Azure Site Recovery</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Support for Linux major OS upgrades with Azure Site Recovery</title><description>You can now perform major Linux OS version upgrades — without disabling Azure Site Recovery, interrupting their replication, or losing existing recovery points. This is supported on RHEL and SLES. (e.g. update from RHEL 8 to RHEL 9). This simplifies the O</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:12 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-17T16:30:12Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530078</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530078</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Migration</category><category>Azure Site Recovery</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Support 5x churn in Azure Site Recovery </title><description>Azure Site Recovery now supports up to 5x churn (500 MB/s per VM). This major enhancement empowers customers to confidently run high IOPS workloads with Azure Site Recovery, ensuring robust disaster recovery for even the most demanding applications like d</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:12 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-17T16:30:12Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">530073</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=530073</link><category>Launched</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Migration</category><category>Azure Site Recovery</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Capacity guidance for Azure Site Recovery</title><description>Azure Site Recovery now offers alternative VM Size recommendations during ASR failover when the current target VM Size may have limited allocation availability due to capacity constraints. This feature enhances disaster recovery by providing guidance on s</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:30:12 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-17T16:30:12Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">509686</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=509686</link><category>Compute</category><category>Mobile</category><category>Web</category><category>App Service</category><category>Retirements</category><title>Retirement: Support for Python 3.10 ends on October 1st, 2026</title><description>On October 1, 2026 extended
support for Python 3.10 will end. Your
apps that are hosted on App Service will continue to run, but security updates will
no longer be available, and we’ll no longer provide customer service for Python 3.10. Learn more about A</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 21:15:14 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-14T21:15:14Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">499906</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=499906</link><category>Retirements</category><title>Retirement: Windows Server 2022 on Azure Kubernetes Service enabled by Azure Arc</title><description>Announcing the  retirement of Windows Server 2022 on Azure Kubernetes Service enabled by Azure Arc in October 2026. </description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:00:13 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-14T18:00:13Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523086</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523086</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Pod CIDR expansion in Azure CNI Overlay for AKS</title><description>Pod CIDR expansion in Azure CNI
Overlay for AKS is now available in public preview. To meet the growing demands of dynamic and large-scale
Kubernetes workloads, Azure Kubernetes Service now offers Pod CIDR Expansion in
public preview for clusters using Az</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:30:37 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-14T16:30:37Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523100</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523100</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: eBPF host routing in Advanced Container Networking Services for AKS</title><description>eBPF host routing in Advanced Container Networking Services for AKS is now available in public preview. As containerized applications scale across distributed environments,
traditional networking approaches can introduce latency and reduce throughput.
To </description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 16:00:47 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-14T16:00:47Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526145</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526145</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure Virtual Network Manager</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Virtual Network Manager UseExisting Mode for UDR management </title><description>Azure Virtual Network Manager
UDR management now offers UseExisting mode, providing customers with greater
flexibility and compliance control over user-defined routes (UDRs). With the UseExisting mode, Azure
Virtual Network Manager detects and appends req</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:30:39 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-13T18:30:39Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526160</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526160</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure Virtual Network Manager</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Virtual Network Manager IP Address Management Pool Association Recommendation</title><description>Azure Virtual Network Manager
IP Address Management (IPAM) – Pool Association Recommendation is now generally
available,
bringing intelligent, large-scale automation to IP address management in Azure. As
organizations expand their network footprint across</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:00:24 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-13T17:00:24Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526155</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526155</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Azure Virtual Network Manager</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Virtual Network Manager peering compliance </title><description>Azure Virtual Network Manager peering
compliance is now generally available, providing a secure and compliant mechanism to
protect network connectivity managed by Azure Virtual Network Manager. In
large-scale environments, it’s essential to prevent uninte</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:00:24 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-13T17:00:24Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526895</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526895</link><category>Launched</category><category>Developer tools</category><category>Visual Studio</category><category>Visual Studio Code</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: .NET 10 </title><description>.NET 10 delivers a faster, more secure, and more capable platform for modern development. This release enhances performance, productivity, and security across the stack—while C# 14 introduces refinements that make coding more natural and expressive. With </description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:15:02 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-12T17:15:02Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523787</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523787</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Azure Database for MySQL</category><title>[Launched] General Availability: Server Parameters support for lower_case_table_names in Azure Database for MySQL- Flexible Server </title><description>We are thrilled to announce the General Availability of a highly requested feature: Self-serve configuration of the lower_case_table_names server parameter during server creation. For MySQL version 8.0+ you can configure lower_case_table_names only when y</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:00:15 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-12T17:00:15Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523134</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523134</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Scheduler profile configuration for AKS </title><description>Organizations running complex workloads on Kubernetes often face
challenges in optimizing pod placement for performance, cost, or resource
efficiency. To address this, Azure Kubernetes Service now offers scheduler
profile configuration with in-tree plugin</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:00:15 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-12T17:00:15Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">508390</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=508390</link><category>Launched</category><category>Databases</category><category>Azure Database for MySQL</category><category>Features</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure Database for MySQL Triggers for Azure Functions </title><description>Azure Database for MySQL triggers for Azure Functions are now generally available, enabling you to set up change tracking and develop event-driven applications at scale on any MySQL table. You can trigger a function when a row in a MySQL table is created,</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:00:15 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-12T17:00:15Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523062</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523062</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Agentic CLI for AKS </title><description>Diagnosing and resolving issues in Kubernetes clusters can
be complex and time-consuming, especially when navigating logs, telemetry, and
diagnostics manually. To simplify this experience, Azure Kubernetes Service is
introducing a new agentic AI-powered C</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:00:09 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T20:30:22Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523057</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523057</link><category>Launched</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: LocalDNS for AKS</title><description>LocalDNS for AKS is
now generally available.   Large-scale Kubernetes clusters often face DNS resolution
delays and reliability issues, especially during upstream outages or high query
volumes. To address this, Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) now offers Lo</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:45:46 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T17:45:46Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526468</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526468</link><category>In preview</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Migration</category><category>Azure Migrate</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Insights in Azure Migrate</title><description>Azure Migrate now offers integrated Security insights, allowing customers to assess potential risks within their on-premises environment. The solution delivers actionable recommendations to effectively mitigate these risks as part of the migration plannin</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:30:08 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T17:30:08Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523975</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523975</link><category>Launched</category><category>Storage</category><category>Management and governance</category><category>Archive Storage</category><category>Azure Backup</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Vaulted Backup for Azure Data Lake Storage (ADLS)</title><description>Azure Backup vaulted protection
for ADLS Gen2 delivers secure, off‑site backups to help organizations meet
resilience and compliance goals. Vaulted backups maintain an independent copy
of your data, isolated from the source account - providing protection </description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:16:01 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T17:16:01Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">526720</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=526720</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Azure Firewall</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: DNS flow trace logs for Azure Firewall </title><description>Azure Firewall now
supports DNS flow trace logs — a new logging capability that gives you deep,
end-to-end visibility into DNS traffic and name resolution paths. This
enhancement provides richer telemetry to help you troubleshoot, validate, and
secure DNS</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:00:09 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T17:00:09Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523172</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523172</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Azure Linux OS Guard for AKS </title><description>Cloud-native workloads face increasingly sophisticated
threats—from rootkits and container escapes to unauthorized code execution—that
demand stronger security guarantees. To address these challenges, Microsoft has
introduced Azure Linux with OS Guard, no</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:00:09 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T17:00:09Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">523067</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=523067</link><category>In preview</category><category>Compute</category><category>Containers</category><category>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</category><title>[In preview] Public Preview: Flatcar Container Linux for AKS </title><description>Maintaining consistent and secure node configurations in
Kubernetes environments can be challenging due to issues like configuration
drift, manual changes, and complex upgrade paths. These challenges often lead
to unpredictable behavior and increased oper</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:00:09 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T17:00:09Z</a10:updated></item><item><guid isPermaLink="false">513802</guid><link>https://azure.microsoft.com/updates?id=513802</link><category>Launched</category><category>Networking</category><category>Security</category><category>Azure Front Door</category><category>Web Application Firewall</category><category>Security</category><category>Features</category><title>[Launched] Generally Available: Azure WAF JavaScript challenge on Azure Front Door</title><description>Announcing the general availability of JavaScript (JS) challenge for Azure Web Application Firewall (WAF) with Azure
Front Door To strengthen bot mitigation strategies,
Azure WAF now introduces JS challenge as a new security feature. The
JS challenge prov</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:00:09 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2025-11-11T17:00:09Z</a10:updated></item></channel></rss>